Mr Cai, it's my responsibility
Mr Cai
Please speak
I have researched on some similar cases from overseas
For cases like these
We can get the school to organise a professors' union
to have a disucssion with the related parties' embassy
We will utilize diplomatic relations to mediate
If mediation fails
We will then go to the courts to file a lawsuit
Zhong Pu
It seems like these people
Did not sleep a wink last night
Mr Cai
Those who could not sleep last night
were not just us
De Qian, Ban Nong, Yi Han
and students Guo Xin Gang, Deng Zhong Xia
Many students spent the whole night
At the liberal arts office doing research
Deng Zhong Xia and the students still did drafting
Students of Peking University
drafted a a letter of resistance to the British Embassy
and an open letter to the Beiyang Government
in case of need
I, Cai Yuan Pei, have done a good job as Peking University Principal
I thank everyone for their support
Alright
Since everyone is on the same page,
there is no need to continue debating
I will call Fu Zeng Tian immediately
to tell him Peking University's stance
also, everyone should prepare
quickly organise the professors and student unions
and get ready
Mr Zhong Pu will be in charge of this matter
Does anyone have any objections?
No
Brother Buo Tang, I am reporting that
Peking University Committee members
strongly disagree with Ke De Lai
and the British Embassy's appeal
We must protect our country's sovereignty
and Peking University's rights
Alright
So, you are clear about
the consequences of your actions
and have a plan of action?
Aren't I here to ask for your help
Tell me
What should we do?
First you will have to obtain
Fu Zeng Xiang's empathy and support
I have already spoken with him
What did he say?
He just said he would resign
He is trying to shirk responsibility
Regardless.
I am still thankful to the both of you
Look,
I'll treat you to lunch this afternoon,
alright?
Sure
Openly trying to woo key government officials
Please just do me this favour
Alright
Come
Please come in
How are the both of you?
You just sampled our shaoxing cuisine
Does it suit your palate?
We are obliged to help you since you have treated us
What schemes do you have?
Duan Qi Rui is going to listen to the reports this afternoon
If we can't get through this obstacle,
Both of us will have to resign
That's right
This issue is urgent and serious
This morning, Zhu Er Dian
called 3 times to ask about the outcome
Alright
Please drink some tea
If that's the case
Let me explain the situation to the both of you
I will be honest
Peking University Committee members
none of them are cowards
The meeting this morning
Before I finished speaking
The whole atmosphere was tense
Everyone decided
to fight till the end
We will never embarrass this country and Peking University
So how do you plan to fight?
We will form a professor's union and have discussions with the British Embassy
What if you don't come to a conclusion?
We will then go to court
What about Duan Qi Rui?
He is a temperamental warlord
Duan Qi Rui is still Chinese after all
He can't possibly betray his ancestors
We will reason with him
I don't think he will be receptive to
Those pathetic idelogies of yours
What are you saying
How are they pathetic?
Firstly, we have documents about the 2 governments
It is enough to prove that
Ke De Lai's dismissal is legal
Secondly, we have strong evidence
To prove that Ke De Lai's dismissal is logical
As a government official
Duan Qi Rui will be
The one who protects our rights
He will not betray us right?
I can say this very confidently
Duan Qi Rui will never pay heed to
Whatever you are suggesting
Cai Zi Min don't try to fool us
Please reveal what you have up your sleeve
You know me so well Brother Bo Tang
Apart from the evidence I mentioned
We will give Minister Duan
2 items
The first is a letter written by Peking University Staff and Students
To the government
The other item is a letter of resistance
Written by Peking University students to the British Embassy
Are you sure these items are useful?
Of course
Cai Zi Min, you are good
This is sly of you
You have targeted Duan Qi Rui's weak spot
Mr Fu
Take these items with you
when you meet Duan Qi Rui in the afternoon
I guarantee you he will not only be able control his anger
he will also beg for your help
At that time, tell him to look for me
Both of you are making me confused
This matter cannot be clear enough
Duan Qi Rui knows how important this matter is
I never thought
Brother Zi Min could be so cunning
I'm in awe of you
Please don't
I learned it all from him
You take on the characteristics of those closest to you
Both of you are sly as foxes
Zhong Pu
Master Cai
Mr Cai
Quickly
Inside
Brother Zhong Pu
Good news
Shou Chang
Shou Chang, you still remember me
Mr Cai, what good news do you bring
Duan Qi Rui approved of our idea
he wants Peking University's professor's union
to quickly hold talks with the British embassy
To resolve Ke De Lai's issue
Alright
Also, Fu Zeng Xiang mentioned
Duan Qi Rui emphasised that
He does not want Peking University students
to protest in the streets
or to attack the embassy
and to avoid confrontations with the foreigners
Wang Da also mentioned just now
He wants us to quickly prepare the materials for the talks
He has arranged to meet with Zhu Er Dian
Now the materials and evidence have been prepared
The backup team will be led by Deng Zhong Xia
together with Fu Si Nian and Zhang Luo
The students are very enthusiastic
Just that those involved in the talks
I am still thinking of who should go
At first I was thinking that She Zhi,
Shou Chang and I will be a group
She zhi will be the main speaker
Shou Chang will be in charge of the materials
This is wonderful
Brother Zhong Pu
I have a small suggestion
Please share
See if you can get Gu Hong Ming to join
His English is good
and another reason
Hong Ming has influence overseas
Especially those foreigners in China
They respect him a lot
We did think about that
But we thought he was too eccentric
He has many idiosyncrasies
We are afraid he will not agree to come
and also that he will come and make a scene
It seems that you don't know Gu Hong Ming
He really
Detests those arrogant foreigners
If he gets wind of this matter
He will be receptive
He will spare no effort in the talks
He has experience
and he will definitely be enthusiastic
Of course he has his quirks
He likes to keep score
When you go to invite him
please humble yourself and say some flattering words
Zhong Pu, if you treat him to a meal
If he has any requests
try your best to fulfill them
Alright, I will try
Be or not to be
That is the question
Whether it is noble to suffer the stings and arrows of misfortune
Or to take arms against a sea of trouble
And die
Opposing end them
This is what the great British writer
Shakespeare wrote in "Hamlet"
A famous monologue
and the Danish Prince Hamlet's
Reflection on his life and destiny
I want to ask all the students seated
Who has thought about such issues
You should seriously reflect on this question
Because the answer to this will be you life's purpose
With the correct life purpose
your life will have a direction
you will have a bright future
We study English poems
and the English language
to be able to expouse Chinese values
and our gentle yet meaningful poems
to far flung lands
Those who cannot remember will continue to stand
Thank you Professor
Good Day
Bye Teacher
Sir
Guests?
Professor Gu
Are you here to learn English?
Or
Professor Gu, we are here to seek you as a master
How interesting
You speak in the vernacular language
Yet come here to learn English poems
Doesn't make sense