Age of Awakening
Episode 10
What the whole world believes in
The spirit of the Chinese People
Is now being manipulated by the various warlords
This country is finished
Its ruined
Bai Sha
You are a man of culture
You are not suited for politics
Please do not plunge into despair
How about you join me to teach in Beijing University
We will write a new book
To rebuild the citizen's mindset
No, no no
Zhong Pu, I won't follow you to Beijing University
I am telling you
What you said about avoiding politics for 20 years is wrong
It's impossible!
What's left is to fight with this ruined society
I will fight with all my life
Brother Meng Zou! Brother Meng Zou!
Mr Liu
Welcome Mr Liu
This is Mr Zhu Pu
Nice to meet you, Mr Zhu Pu
Nice to meet you as well
Brother Meng Zou,
I've heard that Mr Zhong Pu has arrived in Shanghai from Beijing
I've come to see him
That's great, welcome
I hope I'm not inconveniencing anyone
No, you are not
Please come in
Let's sit inside
Come
Thank you
Mr Zhong Pu please excuse this small gift
You are too gracious
Please sit
Mr Zhong Pu
I am here to discuss with you
Matters involving the children
Now the country is facing internal strife
Because of Zhang Xun's restoration, lessons have stopped
Even if we resume lessons
It will be during the next semester
Countless wars are happening overseas
So they want to go to France to work and study
I'm afraid we can't provide a schedule at such short notice
Mr Liu, what do you intend to do then?
I do not want to disrupt our children's futures
So I was thinking if both our families can work together
and send the 3 of them to America to study
I'll handle the paperwork
and expenses
Mr Liu,
This is already the second time you have brought this up
I appreciate your concern
and understand your feelings
But I will tell you frankly
I cannot agree to this
All these things
I think Mr Zhong Pu
has prepared for Yan Nian and Qiao Nian right?
Yes indeed
Parents want the best for their children
Mr Zhong Pu, Liu Mei is my only daughter
So I understand how you feel
I can really understand
a father's love for his children
But Mr Zhong Pu,
regarding this matter,
why are you so steadfast in your choice?
Mr Liu, please do not misunderstand
it's not being steadfast
Firstly I'm not able to decide on Yan Nian's behalf
Secondly Yan Nian
will never accept others' help
Let me tell you honestly
I'm worried about his attitude
because Yan Nian
is too disciplined and confident
I am not able to convince him
I feel extremely guilty
that as his father
I have no rights to speak
Mr Zhong Pu
The 2 children
are already in a relationship
So I feel that
as elders
we should care about their future
This is an issue
The 2 children
are in what kind of relationship?
They
I'm not sure if I can explain it clearly
I understand
I'll talk to him
We need to establish the facts first
So we don't make any mistakes
Let me handle it
After I get an answer
We'll speak again
Thank you so much
You're too gracious
I'll take my leave first
Why don't you stay for a meal
No no no
I know you haven't finished your previous discussion
No need to send me off
Alright, take your time
I'll wait for your response
Alright
Bai Sha
On the day of Zhang Xin's restoration
Li Da Zhao was forced to leave Beijing
He roamed about for countless months
and fell to the lowest rungs of society
to observe national sentiments
and to clear his thoughts
desperately finding a way to save his country
The restoration of Zhang Xun
signaled that
the plan for the establishment of a bourgeois republic in China
was completely stopped
A painful lesson
hastened the reform of the bourgeois
and caused a change in perception and criticism
The modern Chinese
started to realize
that just relying on transplanting
western political ideology and methods
would not save China
Saving China would require starting from the basics
Apart from a cultural awakening
and enlightenment,
it is necessary to listen to the voices of the people
to find a suitable solution to reform China
Come here
Zhong Pu
Where is he
Uncle Wang
My father wouldn't have left right?
No, he wouldn't have
He would not have left before seeing the both of you
Even if he had left, he wouldn't have gone far
Would he have gone to Ji Xi?
to see Hu She?
I told you we shouldn't have come
Qiao Nian, let's go
Brother!
Yan Nian!
These are the buns your aunt steamed
I was afraid it would spoil in the hot weather so I heated it up again
Come
Yan Nian, come
Listen to Uncle
Come
Sit here
Look
I told you he hasn't left yet
He went to steam buns for you
Yesterday
your father said
to send these buns to school
Gao Jun Man helped me to steam it
he told me to eat it while travelling
It's quite a lot, so help yourself
Come let's eat
It's meat
Please eat, your aunt steamed it for you
Didn't you say it was meant for you
There are 2 different fillings
vegetarian and meat
I've finished the vegetarian filling
the meat filling is for you
Can you stop pretending
since when was there vegetarian fillings
Why do I not know about it?
You have eaten it
Your aunt steamed these buns for you
He intentionally left it for you
so please help yourself to it
Come, eat
Just to eat some buns
and you had to lie about vegetarian fillings
stop pretending
Speak honestly
I've finally managed to see you this time
so let's chat
Let's chat about 2 things
Firstly, the both of you have come out to see the world at such a young age
Makes me relieved to see the both of you so self-reliant
You want to go to France to work and study
I am supportive as well
But now there is a world war going on
there are many complications
Our country is also experiencing internal strife
You can't always remain at this French language centre
If you do not have a long term plan you will definitely have worries
i want to know
What are your thoughts
Both of us will walk this path alone
We won't rely on others and our family
To us, work-study
is the most appropriate path
We plan to study in France
we have a very strong foundation now
we will not give up halfway
So we have decided to remain in Shanghai to study
Ya Dong library's business is doing well
We should be able to work-study with no issues
Most importantly we have many books to read here
We can't bear to leave
That's right
We can go to Beijing during the holidays
Alright, since you have already thought hard about it
I will respect your wishes
Secondly,
can you tell me
what is your relationship with Liu Mei?
What do you mean
Don't you think that
everyone is curious about it?
I'm not surprised that people are curious
I did not expect you to be curious about it as well
Why not?
Because I feel that you
are not such a superficial person
Is it superficial for me to be concerned about you and Liu Mei?
Since you are as superficial as everyone else
I will tell you clearly
that I, Liu Mei and Qiao Nian
have a pure and noble relationship based on mutual cooperation
I don't quite understand
Have you read Peter Kropotkin and Tolstoy's books
Yes I have
So you must know about mutualism
anarchism
and pan-laborism
I know a little
So you should know about
what is mankind's ideal state
I'm all ears
Mankind's most ideal state
is when the whole society
based on their own self discipline continuously
self-improve
Everyone will work together
and form a relationship that transcends familial and romantic ties
Oh, so you and Liu Mei have this sort of relationship
This is what I desire
Then, other people get the impression
that you and her are a couple
A couple?
Like butterfly lovers, do you understand?
This is the difference in our generations
Your generation can't get rid of the obstacle of superficiality
But to us,
that is our goal
What we desire
is an eternal pure and noble friendship
Does Liu Mei have the same understanding as you
Of course
Additionally, I am
imposing a self-discipline rule for myself
I call it the 6 prohibitions
what do you mean
They are no skiving, no watching of shows, no photography
No eating at restaurants, no talking about fashion
But most importantly, no dating, no private relationships
If society is able to be disciplined
and continuously self-improve,
everyone will come together
to form relationships that transcend familial and romantic ties
So doesn't that make me and your aunt
Your aunt and your Uncle Wang
your uncle Wang and you
Liu Mei and I
Liu Mei's parents and your aunt
the same type of relationship?
That would be it
Then why do you address your aunt as mother?
That's just a name
So what do you call me then?
I've always called you Chen Du Xiu
Mr Chen Du Xiu
Alright, I'll leave, please continue eating
Zhong Pu
Zhong Pu where are you going?
I'm going back
Going back where? You didn't even bring your luggage
Here's some more
Eat up
This was given by Mr Chen Du Xiu
Steamed by Miss Gao Jun Man
1917 August 14th
Duan Qi Rui announced
China is officially at war against Germany and Austria
Joining in the world war 1 allied countries
The allied countries and America
Promised the Chinese government that
they will sponsor China and allow China to receive the benefits she deserves
Lu Xun is an excellent writer
His work is far-reaching, deep in content, simple yet majestic
This is
filled with strong literary spirit and style
An absolute masterpiece
Look at it
Yi Mo, you're a great calligrapher and you understand the arts
Tell everyone what this seal means
My verdict is that it is extraordinary
Look at this seal
The words "Beijing university" written in seal script are written vertically
The "Beijing" at the top
Is written such that it looks like 2 people with their backs facing each other
The "university" at the bottom
Looks like a man standing straight
This is a man carrying 2 people on his back
Which then symbolizes a meaning of a crowd
This shows that Beijing University teachers
are shouldering the heavy responsibility of educating the people
Good
Well said!
In my opinion these 2 words
also has a symbolic meaning of being the pillar of society
Looks like it right
Mr Zhou put "Beijing" and "University"
to make it seem like a man's spine
He is trying to convey that Beijing University should become the backbone of this country, shouldering the progress and democracy of this society