[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Fourteen]
My apologies, everybody,
I have a guest from my hometown here.
How about we continue next time?
We haven't fully enjoyed our discussion yet, how come it's over now?
I'm terribly sorry!
[Hu Shi, styled Shizhi, Professor at Peking University]
Professor Hu,
can we say goodbye to you in the Western manner?
Of course!
See you next time, Doctor Hu.
Thanks for coming here.
Come on.
[Wang Mengzou, Manager of Yadong Library]
Thanks.
Goodbye, Doctor Hu.
Thank you.
See you, Doctor Hu.
Come here.
See you next time.
Goodbye, Doctor Hu.
Brother Mengzou,
Doctor Hu.
Don't forget to eat more apples!
For the vitamin.
Sure, thank you!
See you, Doctor Hu.
See you.
Take care.
Brother Mengzou, it's been a while.
Good to see you!
Come over here to sit.
Here...
I'll take it.
Brother Mengzou,
You must be just arriving.
So here is the thing,
now that "New Youth" had
adopted collective editorship,
I'm here to establish the distribution station.
I wasn't able to find Zhongfu, so I decided to come to you.
Brother Zhongfu went to the Shaoxing Guildhall today.
I thought there aren't any female
faculties or students at Peking University.
That's true.
But,
just now...
You're talking about the ladies in my office earlier?
They're members of my poetry club in Beijing.
And they're here to discuss vernacular poetry with me.
No wonder your mother was so worried about you.
Excuse me?
Your mother had a letter sent to me
saying that back in your hometown,
there were loads of gossips,
and rumors about you.
Dongxiu was rather anxious at home.
So was your mother.
Therefore, they asked me to persuade you
to go back home and marry Dongxiu as soon as possible.
You see,
here's the letter.
You should think it over.
What you said got me really confused here.
You see?
What the heck are these?
Sheer nonsense! Brother Mengzou.
I too thought they were completely unfounded, before I arrived here.
Right!
But then, you guys are even talking about "vitamins",
So it's not all rumor after all.
Brother Mengzou, please don't get it wrong.
They're indeed the members of my poetry club in Beijing.
How can I put it, you're just...
But you, you guys were...
That's just common etiquette.
I...
This lad Ren Guangming is still quite the drinker!
Such a rare opportunity,
[Zhou Shuren (Lu Xun), styled Yucai, Civil servant under the Ministry of Education]
for us alumni to gather up in Beijing.
Such a rare gathering.
I forgot to ask Guangming just now
what's Yang Kaiming up to recently.
How come we haven't heard from him in a long time?
Ren Guangming said, after Yang Kaiming graduated from the Normal University，
[Zhou Zuoren, styled Xingshao, Professor at Peking University]
he went back home to teach.
He's a kindhearted fellow.
He often gives financial support to a widow,
which reproached by her clansmen.
There was one day,
Yang Kaiming got drunk,
and fell asleep next to the table at the widow's.
The next dawn, somehow her clansmen got informed,
and then
they detained her for denouncement.
The head of the clan held a meeting.
According to the rules of their clan,
they decided to drown the widow to punish her.
Yang Kaiming was so traumatized hearing what happened that he lost his mind.
Nowadays,
he begs and gibbers on the street all day long.
He won't recognize anybody anymore.
Madness!
People became mad.
So did the world.
Don't!
Don't kill me! Don't kill me!
I don't wanna die!
I'm begging you!
I'm begging you! Please, please don't kill me!
I don't wanna die!
I really don't!
Hey, Jiusun, what on earth...
What do you want?!
Cou..cousin...
Cousin, you got to save me!
Somebody is going to kill me!
What?
They're chasing after me to kill me!
Don't!!
No, no, no!!! Don't open the door!
Don't! Don't open the door!!
Don't open the door!! Don't!!!
But, Jiusun, what's...
They...Listen...
Their footsteps!
Listen you two!
Can't you hear them coming close?
They're holding a 10-inch knife,
very sharp - it's bloody!
It's all bloody outside!!
They're going to kill me with that knife!
I...I don't want to die!
I have to hide.
I have to hide somewhere!
No, hide somewhere...
Jiusun, come over here, come on.
Wait a bit...
No...
I don't wanna die...
I don't wanna die at all!!
You're just a secretary from Taiyuan
coming to visit in Beijing -- nobody knows you here!
Who would kill you?
How come someone wants to kill you?
Come on,
Get out of that first.
Cousin, if I die,
can you bring this letter to my mum and sister?
He looks deranged, must have lost his mind.
Jiusun, you just come out first.
We'll talk it over, is that okay?
I won't go out!
I won't!
Please be good and get out first.
I won't go! Don't drag me!
Just come out please.
Get out!
Hurry up, be good, get out now!
No, I won't, I won't go!
Just come here, will you?
I won't!!
Come over, be good, come on...
They're here!
Just get out first!
I won't go!!!
Jiusun, it's me, Jiusun!
You guys are here.
What on earth happened to him?
On our way to Beijing, Jiusun had
seen many people who were starved to death.
He had a breakdown.
In these few days when we're staying at the inn,
he kept moving into new rooms.
But still he can't sleep at all,
as he was horrified that somebody would kill him.
This morning,
he insisted on coming to you
and that those people are after him again.
It seems that he's having a psychosis.
Let's take him to a hospital first.
Jiusun, Jiusun, let's get out of here!
Come on, Jiusun.
No! Don't touch me!
What are you doing? I won't leave!
Jiusun, it's me!
What are you people doing?
It's me, Jiusun!
What are you doing?
You tell me now, why do you want me dead?
Why are you trying to kill me?
Why kill me?!
Why?!
Tell me why!
Why kill me?!
Tell me!
One pair of silver cups,
two pairs of silver chopsticks,
one felt table cloth,
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhongfu, Dean of Liberal Arts at Peking University]
four handkerchiefs,
Slow down, slow down.
Four handkerchiefs
to express our best wishes for Mr. Shizhi's wedding.
Shen Yimo,
Liu Wendian,
Chen Daqi,
[Gao Yihan, Professor at Peking University]
Ma Xulun,
Cai Yuanpei,
Slow down.
Zhang Shizhao,
Gao Yihan,
Liu Bannong,
Li Dazhao,
and you, Chen Duxiu.
Great! Now Shizhi is back to his hometown for his wedding.
As for this list of wedding gifts,
you guys should make several copies of it
and post them in our offices,
[Liu Bannong, Professor at Peking University]
and by the university entrance.
It's essentially a notice of appeasement.
On one hand, it's a notice to the slanderers
asking them to cut the gossips.
On the other hand,
it's for the female poetry club members who are hankering after him,
so that they stop fantasizing.
Very well done, Zhongfu!
I can finally have a moment of peace!
No need to post the notice outside the dormitory of Shizhi and Yihan.
How so?
Why though?
We should save some opportunities for the female poetry club members.
Even though Shizhi is now married,
Yihan can take over and receive their visits.
I have nothing like Shizhi's charisma.
No can do!