[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Six]
Neither has he gone to a proper university
nor does he have any teaching qualifications.
How can he have a monthly salary
that is 20 dollars more than yours?
You, a master versed in both Chinese and Western learning.
The tide.
The tide of the world is mighty.
Those who submit will prosper; those who resist shall perish.
Brother Jigang, I predict your style of
quoting scriptures, mimicking ancients and
obscurant nonsense will not survive
much longer at Peking University after today.
When did brother Deqian hop on the bandwagon
and become a cheerleader for literary reform?
Not only reform, but thoroughly repudiate those mistaken ways
and turn over a new leaf.
Without eradicating the parallel prose of the Six Dynasties,
without abolishing the demons of the Wenxuan school
and the bastards of the Tongcheng school
Chinese literature has no future.
Aye! Aye!
Well said!
Yes!
Write that down as well.
Exactly!
Mister Qian,
You're even fresher than Chen Duxiu and Hu Shi!
But you know what they say about fresh fish?
He is very fresh indeed!
[insinuation: new, but spoils quickly]
Associate Professor, what is that supposed to mean?
What is that? Ridiculous...
Mister Cai.
Everything is ready.
Just waiting for your inaugural speech.
President Cai is here.
Please be seated.
Gentlemen, students.
On December 26th, in the fifth year of the Republic [1916]
On the order of the President of the Republic of China,
Cai Yuanpei is appointed as the President of Peking University.
As decreed.
Hurrah, hurrah.
Hurrah.
And now we invite President Cai
to deliver his inaugural speech.
Hurrah.
Honoured guests,
Five years ago, when Yan Fu was the president of Peking University,
I served in the Ministry of Education,
as the Minister of Education.
I remember making a small dedication to this school
on the first day of the new term that year.
Gentlemen, many of you have come here from preparatory school.
So you presumably know that
after even three days of absence, a scholar must be regarded with new eyes.
Let alone it's now been several years.
The gentlemen present, when compared to the past,
must have made remarkable progress.
Today, I am here to serve Peking University.
I have three things I would like to share with everyone.
One, hold fast to your purpose.
Coming here to study, you must have a certain purpose.
In order to know whether that purpose is upright or not,
you must first be clear about the university's purpose.
A university is a place for research and deep knowledge.
Now there are people outside Peking University who denounce it
as a corrupt institution.
This is because of those who come here to study
as a shortcut for their ambitions of
of officialdom and wealth.
In their single-minded wish to become officials, to get rich
they care nothing for their professors' depth of learning.
And think only of their bureaucratic rankings.
The higher the rank, the more popular they are.
Their is probably for the favour
of receiving their guidance after graduating.
What I want to say is,
you are coming to study at Peking University
for three or four years.
This cannot be regarded as a long time.
But if you cherish your time and study diligently,
then you can certainly attain a high level of mastery.
If your purpose of coming to Peking University
is to become an official or make a fortune,
then your purpose is mistaken.
And you are bound to go astray in your studies.
Going to brothels regularly and only revising
when there is a test.
Ignoring the surpluses and shortfalls of your learning.
Striving only for marks.
Once the exam is done,
the books are shelved and neglected.
Hardly ever taking an initiative, only carelessly doing the bare minimum.
With the diploma in hand,
so you participate in society in this manner.
Frittering away your time, having learned absolutely nothing.
This is self-defeating.
This is completely contrary
to the true purpose of studying at Peking University.
Perhaps everyone still remembers
the Xinhai Revolution, which happened not long ago.
The reason we wanted a revolution
was because the Qing government was too corrupt.
That there are also many people now
dissatisfied with the status quo
is also because of the moral bankruptcy of society.
Gentlemen, if at this time you do not
build a strong foundation and diligently study,
and by chance you are forced to make a living and become a teacher
you will certainly hinder your students.
If you enter politics,
you will certainly hinder the nation.
This is the hindrance of others.
Harming others and harming yourself.
Therefore your purpose must be righteous.
This is the first of my hopes for you gentlemen.
Good.
That's the Cai Yuanpei I know.
Finding the root of Peking University's ills as soon as he takes office.
Two, encourage moral integrity.
The general tendency of society today
is increasingly one of resignation and apathy.
Soley preoccupied with the present, morally bankrupt.
Moral corruption everywhere you look.
Those without a firm virtuous foundation
are rarely not contaminated by this social ethos.
The nation's rise and fall
depends on the strength or weakness of its customs.
If everyone follows customs of those of the present,
it is impossible to imagine a future.
Therefore, there must be unsurpassed scholars, who by the example
of their own conduct, forcefully overcome these degenerate customs.
Gentlemen, as university students,
you are in a position of high standing,
duty-bound to shoulder these heavy responsibilities.
Virtue without cultivation, learning without conduct,
wallowing in the mire
of these degenerate social norms.
Not only does this disgraceful oneself.
Moreover, an example is set for others.
Therefore,
moral conduct cannot be otherwise,
but a matter treated with rigorous practice.
This is the second of my hopes for you gentlemen.
Three, respect for teachers and friends.
Be completely candid, speak frankly and openly, encourage one another.
Everyone, we are all at Peking University,
we will together both share the glory and bear the shame.
I believe our Peking University is certain to be the home
of cultural experts and leading thinkers.
This concludes my speech.
We will have ample opportunity to continue our discussions.
[Shanghai]
It's Dad!
Dad!
Dad, did you bring us good to eat?
I did, of course I did!
What did you bring?
In the box in the box, find it yourself.
You came back!
Why didn't you send me a telegram?
What telegram?
Weren't I not at home?
I was in a rush.
How are you?
How did the investment offering go?
Not only did the investment offering go smoothly,
but there is another very important thing
I want to tell you.
Mr. Cai Yuanpei
is now the President of Peking University.
He wants me to take the position
of Peking University's Dean of Liberal Arts.
Invited me three times, and I agreed.
Agreed?
I want to be the Dean of Liberal Arts at Peking University
and I can also bring "New Youth"
to Beijing to expand it.
Then we have to move again.
Not so fast.
This is my promise to Mr. Cai.
If I'm competent for three months,
I will stay.
If I'm not competent, I have to go back to Shanghai.
So I want to
go to Beijing alone first.
Go to Beijing alone?
Then...
What about us?
Isn't it just three months in all?
When I get familiar with the work arrangement and residence,
I'll settle down.
If all goes well,
I'll bring you all along.
That will do.
Found it!
I still have a few things to arrange in Shanghai.
You help me pack my bags.
I want to travel light.
Tanghulu!
Tanghulu! Here.
Henian, here's one for you.
Shizhi. The masterpiece "On the Improvement of Literature"
was published with unprecedented impact.
I also hope you, Brother, can give "New Youth" a monthly article.
A thesis or a translation, either one.
A few days ago, I officially gave
Mr. Cai Yuanpei, the new president of Peking University
a recommendation of Brother to become Dean in Liberal Arts.
Because Brother hasn't yet graduated, I temporarily lack a replacement.
Mr. Jiemin hopes that you will return home early
and not take the position of Dean
in order to be a professor of philosophy or literature.
We look forward to you eagerly.
"Su Wu does not disgrace Hu Jie" (?)
"Snowy and ice days"
"Poor for nineteen years"
"Thirsty for snow and hungry for felt"
[Yi Baisha, styled Yuecun, Scholar of the New Culture Movement]
"Shepherding the North Sea" (?)