[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Seventeen]
Sir.
Greetings.
Hello.
Could you tell me where Mr. Cai Yuanpei's office is?
I am Cai Yuanpei.
May I know who you are?
Greetings, Mr Cai.
Hello.
My name is Mao Zedong.
I am from Hunan.
Mao Zedong from Hunan.
Mao Zedong from Hunan?
You are Mr. Yang Changji's student.
That's right.
Mr. Changji is my teacher.
Very good, very good.
Mr. Yang Changji
recommended you to come to Peking University
to attend some of the lectures, right?
Right.
There's no problem attending our lectures,
I made the arrangements myself.
Mr. Changji and I have discussed
and found you a job in Peking University
that will not disrupt lectures,
but will allow you to earn money for food and clothing.
That's great.
Thank you.
I am preparing to
recommend you to Peking University's Red Building Library
to become Li Dazhou's assistant.
Are you alright with this?
Mr. Dazhou's assistant?
Alright.
I'm willing.
Thank you so much.
The pay is a little low.
Only eight dollars a month.
I don't mind.
I'm willing.
Then, let me see.
Alright.
I'll be on my way to find Mr. Shouchang.
I'll bring you to the Red Building.
Come, please.
Sir, please.
Please, you first.
Here.
Right here.
Still busy,
Mr. Shouchang?
Oh my, Mr. Cai.
Wait a bit for me.
Careful.
Alright.
Hello, Mr. Cai.
Isn't this a new batch of books for Peking University?
I've been busy unpacking.
So it's messy.
I see.
Indeed.
In this library,
I always see you working alone.
I got an assistant here for you.
Are you alright with it?
Thank you for saving me.
That's good.
Let me formally introduce to both of you.
This is Peking University Library Director Li Dazhou,
Mr. Li Shouchang.
This is Hunan's
Mr. Mao Zedong, Mr. Mao Renzhi,
from Shaoshan, Hunan.
He's a member of the Xinmin Society
and Mr. Yang Changji's favorite student.
Mr. Dazhou.
I am from Hunan Provincial First Normal University.
Hello, Mr. Dazhao.
Hello.
He just graduated from that university.
His trip to Beijing
is to help out Hunan's French work-study program.
He's taking the opportunity
to come and learn from Peking University
to take a look.
So I decided to find him a job
to become your assistant.
What do you think?
Working in this library is hard work.
Are you ready for it?
Not a problem.
I'm not afraid of hard work.
If you have any work, just tell me.
That's good.
Good.
Runzhi,
if you have any difficulties,
please let me know.
Don't hold back.
Thank you, Mr. Cai.
Good.
I need to hurry for my seminar.
Please.
Take your time.
No hurry.
No worries.
I'll leave you to it.
Alright.
Mr. Dazhou,
let's get to work.
Look,
where shall we begin?
Good, good.
Let's do it.
Help me lift this box of books
and place them there.
Alrighty!
Mr. Dazhou,
it's this box right?
Yes.
Alright.
Good.
Runzhi,
right?
Yes.
Working in the library is hard work.
Sometimes we have to work overtime.
If you stay late you may just stay here for the night.
There's blankets there.
No need to worry.
Thank you.
No problem.
Do you enjoy reading?
I do!
I...
like to read every genre.
What books are you reading recently?
Recently,
I have enjoyed reading
books on anarchism.
In this case,
you're a follower of anarchism?
I won't call myself a follower,
I'm just interested
out of curiosity.
Runzhi,
pass me that book please.
Alright.
Here.
"The Communist Manifesto"
Have you read it?
I've heard of it,
but I haven't read it.
Then,
how about the Russia's October Revolution?
I've heard about it as well,
but I'm not sure.
It's alright.
After today,
we will be clear on it.
This side's almost done.
Runzhi,
let's move this shelf over there.
Alright.
Be careful of the books on top.
Slowly.
Lift it up.
Give me a hand.
One, two, three.
Alright.
This way.
Peking University
has imported a new batch of books.
If you're willing,
I can give you the job
of editing the catalogue.
This way,
you'll be able to learn from your experience.
You will be the first to read those books.
Thank you so much!
Mr. Shouchang,
can I read them now?
Of course.
Come.
Let's go.
What did you say?
I'm saying the incident of the police arresting students,
was a scheme planned by Zhang Fengzai,
a student of our school.
Sir, regarding such immoral students,
we should expel him immediately.
Do you have evidence?
I am the evidence.
I saw with my own eyes him speaking with the police.
It was he who asked the police to come.
Also that day we were performing,
there were people making a scene.
Those people were under the orders of Liu Yipin.
Everyone present witnessed it.
He called the police over.
It doesn't mean anything.
He saw them fighting
and called the police, it's a logical action.
We were performing!
Why would we be fighting?
When those gangsters were making a scene,
why did the police come?
Why did the police come
and arrest us?
This is such a simple explanation.
Why don't you understand?
Student Xingang, Don't worry.
What I mean is,
we can't just base it on what you say.
This Liu Yipin you mentioned,
we will question him.
If it's what you say it is,
we will take the necessary action.
The truth is right in front of your eyes, what more do you need?
Sir, are you deliberately defending
Zhang Fengzai and Liu Yipin?
How can you speak this way?
Everything must be evidence-based,
I can't simply listen to your side alone.
Other students will then think
that I am biased towards you.
What should I do then?
Indeed.
You cannot make baseless accusations.
Student Guo Xingang,
I remember in my class
you frequently had arguments with Zhang Fengzai.
You are not taking this opportunity to defame him aren't you?
Mr. Song, you know me well.
I will not do such things.
I believe you wouldn't,
but we need evidence.
If you have evidence, we will talk.
But...
Teacher Song,
did you pass those documents that I asked you to?
Not yet, there's still some details
that we need to finetune.
I don't understand.
As a librarian's assistant,
what do you do all day?
What's the matter?
Student, what's wrong?
He's saying we're too slow.
Student,
I apologise.
There are too many students borrowing books today.
Sorry to take up your time.
You think you can placate me with an apology?
Saying there are too many students is an excuse.
Are you saying it is our fault for borrowing books?
You should reflect on your actions
and not push the blame to the students.
Student,
please calm down.
That's not what I meant.
Look,
there really is a large number of students borrowing books today.
We
are a little slow in looking for the books.
How about this,
tell me what book you are looking for.
I'll look for it for you.
I'm not talking to you.
I want to speak to Mr. Li Dazhou personally
and make a complaint to the school.
Mr. Chen.
New assistant librarian,
what's going on?
Well,
today,
there are many people borrowing books.
We are a little slow looking for the books.
This student is getting impatient.
You're from Hunan?
Yes.
Yi Baisha's student.
Mao Zedong, Mao Runzhi.
Yes.
Chen Duxiu,
nice to meet you.
Hello, Mr. Chen.
I've read your essay.
I really like your writing.
Student Fu Sinian,
the number of students borrowing books really is high today.
It is only natural that the speed is slower.
I don't think this situation needs to be like this.
He's new here,
please be more understanding.
Don't nitpick.
Alright?
Now that you've said it, sir,
I won't be borrowing this book today then.