[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Sixteen]
This is...
a rattle-drum.
Who made the rattle-drum?
My older brother.
And your windmill?
Also my older brother.
Also your older brother. Wow.
These two kids are very sensible.
How many Tang poems can you recite?
Shizi,
look who's here.
Auntie.
You've come.
Older sister dragged me to the theatre.
[Wife of Hu Shi, Jiang Dongxiu]
I couldn't decline.
You should have come long ago.
Mother, mother.
Hello Mr. Cai, Mr. Wu.
Hello.
I'm not embarrassing you?
You are my wife.
How could you embarrass me?
Come, let's make some introductions.
Cai Yuanpei, Mr. Cai.
Mr. Wu Zhihui.
Hello, Mr. Cai.
Hello, Mr. Wu.
Hello.
Gentlemen, this is my wife, Jiang Dongxiu.
Mistress Hu, you are quite renowned.
I heard you trapped Hu Zhi on an ox-cart
and wouldn't leave until he was forced
to propose in public.
What a heroine! You have my respect.
Wu, you madman,
always with the crazy talk.
Dongxiu, don't mind him.
Enjoy the play.
Raise this curtain a bit.
Mr. Dazhao.
Is this position ok?
Straighten it. It's fine if it's tidy.
Sure.
Match it.
Are the students behind the curtain ready?
Yes.
Mr. Cai,
Brother Zhongfu,
this side is in order. Please take your seats.
Great.
Everyone, please.
Perhaps it's better if I went back home.
Dongxiu, you've already taken
the first step today.
There will be many occasions like this in the future.
Will you never publicly accompany me?
Madam Hu,
Shizhi, Dongxiu,
go ahead, hand in hand.
Let's go.
Dongxiu,
look,
it's it lively?
This is political street theater the students put together themselves.
Take a look.
Isn't it exciting?
Wow, what's going on?
Bound feet!
Hello, Madam Hu.
Mr. Dazhao.
Hello Mr. Dazhao.
Come, sit here.
Let me give a quick explanation.
The Red Building Book Club
with the support of Peking University's student council
used extracurricular time
to produce a political street play.
It is adapted from "A Reply to Wang Jingxu"
from the third issue of the fourth volume of "New Youth."
Today's performance
is a debrief of sorts
for the editorial board
of "New Youth."
Mr. Cai and Mr. Wu
have long written for "New Youth."
They are also the non-staff editors of "New Youth."
Madam Chen and Madam Hu are specially invited guests.
If I'd know Madam Hu were also coming,
I would have asked my own wife to come and take a look too.
Welcome, Madam Hu.
Without further ado,
students, let's begin!
Like a match that ignites with friction,
and lights the dark night sky.
Like the resonant call of a bugle
that clears a space where people's thoughts can freely soar.
The rallying cry of "New Youth"
is the agitation inside a mother's belly
of an infant singing to be free.
The Red Building's dawn
is that match that lights
ten thousand red clouds at sunrise.
This rallying cry
has provoked so many scowls
from traditionalists.
This dawn
has guided so many warriors
to bravely walk towards battle.
We present "Chime of the Red Building Bell."
T'is I, Wang Jingxuan,
who once crossed easterly, to mythical Japan, studying law and government.
Upon repatriation, to see such moral turpitude and decline!
A fall
of one thousand leagues.
Young scholars slandering the canon at the slightest pretext.
belittling and throwing away Confucian texts.
Instigating evil doctrine to abolish the family.
Driving apart father and son,
poisoning relations between husband and wife.
All of this, caused by the new teachings.
Today,
this old man will go to "New Youth"
and give them a tongue-lashing.
Let's go!
Hurrah!
Get on the horse.
Giddy-up!
Let's go!
Knock Knock Knock
Bang Bang Bang
Bang
Hurrah!
How come there's nobody here?
Let me smoke a pipe while I wait.
Well done!
Is there a living soul here or not?
There is.
Who?
Look, it's older brother.
I'm a journalist at "New Youth."
If I may ask, sir, why are you here?
The supposedly noble publication "New Youth"