[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Twelve]
It's hard to define.
In retrospect,
a lot of what "New Youth" discussed
turned out to be current affairs.
What most of the readers are interested in turned out to be current affairs as well.
So as far as I can see,
since we are trying to gain more positions,
we've got to have an objective,
something that the younger generation cares about the most at the moment.
I agree.
There's no need to confine ourselves.
We should simply discuss
whatever people are most interested in.
Don't be hedged in rules and regulations.
Please come in.
Sir,
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs called for you with urgent matters.
Shall we...
Just say it here.
There is no need to keep it away from the others.
Minister Wang said on the phone
the British professor Cartwright, who was dismissed by our university,
wrote to the British Prime Minister
and complained about Peking University.
The British embassy presented a note to the Republican government.
It startled Feng Guozhang and Duan Qirui.
Minister Wang said that you have caused big trouble this time.
That's why he wanted to see you immediately.
Okay, I'm aware of that now.
But the matter of dismissing Cartwright
is supposed to be relevant to the Ministry of Education.
Why is the Ministry of Foreign Affairs getting involved now?
Anyway, go prepare the sedan for me please.
Brother Zhongfu, sit down first.
I'm leaving for the Ministry of Foreign Affairs now.
As for the lecture series,
I think it's better to call them academic lectures.
Let's try to limit the theme to New Culture.
Specifically, we can focus on topics like writing characters reform,
vernacular essays, vernacular poems,
even funeral affairs or folk customs.
But for politics,
let's try to avoid that,
in case the government intervenes.
This include
Sun Yat-sen's military government,
the melee of war lords, and such.
We should refrain from talking about all of these.
In such an eventful and precarious time,
we can easily get in troubles.
Let's not discuss politics.
Zhongfu,
you're still in charge of the discussions.
Everyone here can participate,
and feel free to pick your own topics,
as long as we form a New Culture-themes lecture series.
I'll also join you.
Sir,
we don't wish to continue the discussion anymore.
I just want to ask
how can the British Government interfere
with our dismissal of Cartwright?
And how can we simply allow such interference to happen?
I'm not aware of the details myself.
This is why I need to go to the Ministry of Foreign Affairs now.
Alright.
Department of Liberal Arts has to be mentally prepared anyway.
I think there's going to be a lawsuit.
I'm leaving.
Shizhi, with regard to the discussion of academics and current affairs
this is what I think...
Hang on a moment,
let's not talk about
that for now.
Let's talk about Cartwright instead.
Good point.
This is the actual position gaining.
Sit down please.
Preposterous!
It doesn't make any sense.
How come they're poking their nose
into our internal affairs?
The most ridiculous part is that
we dismissed him for fair reasons.
How can he complain about us?
Brother Jiemin, you're finally here!
It seems that the chancellor of Peking University
is much busier than me!
How can I compare to you?
Whenever master Wang speaks
the humble me, Cai Yuanpei, will have to rush down here in a split second.
Alright then,
please state your instructions.
If it's not for something extremely urgent,
I wouldn't have disturbed Chancellor Cai.
The dismissal of the foreign professor at Peking University
caused big trouble.
Cartwright turned out to be a descendant of British aristocracy.
He wrote to their Prime Minister Lloyd-George
complaining about you Cai Yuanpei overstepping your authority, your breaching of contract
and discrimination against British citizens.
He's demanding apologies, compensation and resumption of their posts
for both himself and other discharged British personnel
from Peking University.
Lloyd-George
assigned the British Envoy
John Newell Jordan to handle this complaint.
The British Embassy
had already presented a note to our government.
Both Feng Guozhang and Duan Qirui
had ordered me to take care of this matter immediately.
Brother Botang, this sounds really interesting to me.
Peking University is a Chinese national university.
The hiring and discharging of teaching personnel
are the rights and responsibilities entrusted by the state.
How are these relevant to
British Prime Minister and British embassy?
Furthermore, there were prior cases of
discharging foreign personnel
at Peking University, Tsinghua University, Beiyang University and other schools.
There has never been any issues before.
Why is it all of a sudden a big trouble
when I'm involved?
Cartwright complaint about you based on two grounds:
one is that his contract at Peking university
was signed by Ministry of Education.
Peking University has no authority to terminate his contract.
The other is that the term of his contract is 4 years.
What Peking University is doing now is breaching of contract,
which is illegal.
This is simple.
We can terminate his contract through Ministry of Education.
As for breach of contract, that is sheer nonsense.
The contract has it written in black and white:
those who are incompetent at their jobs,
and those who violated the school's regulations
can be discharged.
Strictly speaking,
his incompetency at teaching duties
caused losses to our university.
It was HIM who breached the contract.
We're supposed to hold HIM accountable.
Brother Jiemin,
the situation is for more complicated than what you imagined.
The British Embassy presented a note of protest,
and turned the case into a diplomatic event.
There's no small matter in diplomacy,
not to mention during times of war.
Duan Qirui asked me to tell you
our government had already declared to join the world war.
Both China and Britain are Allies.
We're are on the same boat.
He hopes Peking University would focus on the big picture
and wouldn't harm the relationship
between China and Britain because of this matter.
It seems like this actually caused some troubles.
Some big troubles.
Otherwise I wouldn't have anxiously urged you to come here.
If you didn't show up,
I would have visited you anyway.
Okay then.
You're the mastermind, you tell me what to do.
The first big step towards Peking University's reform got tripped.
Can you tell me how can I continue my jobs as the chancellor?
Not to mention
it concerns the our national dignity and general fairness,
how am I supposed to explain this to the students and faculties of our university?
Brother Jiemin, I understand your difficulties.
But this is
indeed a thorny issue
that is not likely to be resolved all by your sole will.
I think it's better not to act on impulse.
Why don't you go back and discuss the issue with your faculties?
Once you guys reached a consensus,
we can discuss the plans for the next steps.
Brother Botang,
Discharging unqualified foreign personnel
like Cartwright
was a decision collectively made by the appraisal committee of Peking University!
To overthrow this decision,
it has to go through the school appraisal committee,
As far as I can tell,
it is almost impossible to revoked.
Brother Jiemin,
I invited you here
to follow the orders and carry out my duties.
Likewise, your conveying the message to your employees
can be considered as fulfilling your duties.
Exactly how you're going to do it
is Peking University's liberty.
We'll talk further after you guys make up your mind.
Is that alright?
Jiang, we're not going back to Peking University.
Let's go directly to Ministry of Education.
Ya!
Zhongfu, you guys are both here.
Mr. Cai.
It's good that you're both here.
I'm glad you happen to arrive.
We created a program
for the New Culture lecture series.
All of the topics are substantial.
Mr. Cai.
Brother Zhongfu, can I have some water?
What happened.
Shouchang,
please use a large bowl.
You two can take a look.
Zhongfu, Zhongfu, Brother Zhongfu.
Gangster logic!
Zhongfu, you cannot do this!
Pushing us too hard!
We can't do this!
This is the copy of démarche.
We only have this one copy.
We cannot destroy it!
Let's hurry up and discuss
how to cope with this.
Pay no attention to it! Do things in our own ways!
I knew you'd have this kind of response.
Isn't that your response as well?
This matter is rather complicated.
This fellow Cartwright had written a complaint
to his Prime Minister Lloyd-George.
Lloyd-George gave his orders
to the British Envoy Jordan.
And the Envoy Jordan presented a note
to our government.
This whole thing turned into a diplomatic event.
Feng Guozhang and Duan Qirui of our government
both gave specific orders.
So did Ministry of Education.
What about the position Peking University should take?
They only gave us 7 words:
consider the big picture, minimize the problems.
How can we minimize it?
We've already put up the public notice!
The die is cast. Can we simply eat our own words?
This is why I said it's a thorny issue.
I have already inform the school
to have a appraisal committee meeting tomorrow morning,
to discuss this matter.
What is there to be discussed?
Are we supposed to surrender out sovereignty rights under humiliating terms?
Are we supposed to surrender to the foreigners?
Mr. Cai, we have to take this matter seriously!
Du Qirui exhorted again and again,
saying that
during this time of war, Britain is our ally.
We save their face, instead of saving a little only to lose a lot
and harm the interest of the nation.
It is sovereignty that is the biggest interest of a nation.
Who is right, who is wrong? There's no need to debate.
You're right.
Okay then, now that it is a diplomatic event,
our Peking University and Cartwright
can be seen as the representatives of the interests of our nations.
Our Peking University holds in her one hand the national honor
the other had general fairness.
Losing either one of these
would be a crime to our nation.
Well-said Zhongfu!
Let's talk about it right now
how are we going to hold
the school appraisal committee meeting tomorrow.
Alright?
Sure!
Everybody, the current situation is not optimistic.
Cartwright had already demanded that
Peking University apologize to him, offer him compensation
and revoke our decision to dismiss him.
At the same time, the British Embassy presented a note to our government.
Feng Guozhang and Duan Qirui here
gave us direct orders.
Ministry of Foreign Affairs and Ministry of Education both
asked us to resolve the issue in a short period of time.
Just now the Minister of Education Fu Zengxiang called
and said the British Embassy
is waiting for our response.
What should Peking University do?
To surrender or to fight?
Please state your opinions.
Let's start from Zhongfu.
After I learned what happened from Mr. Cai,
I was furious.
This suddenly brought my mind
back to the Opium War happened more than 70 years ago.
How did the Western invaders bully our China?
How did they plunder our nation?
Even back then,
the British government
used the excuse of protecting British citizens in China
to open the gate of our country
with their powerful navy and advanced weaponry.
Our Chinese nation thus started to decline.
Today, they are playing their same old tricks.
Again, using protecting their citizen in China as an excuse,
they are even trying to interfere with
the internal affairs of our university!
What is this?
Plain robbery!
If this can be tolerated, what cannot?
My view is pretty clear,
Peking University cannot surrender!
If we do, we'll become sinners to our own history.
Dear colleagues,
I came back to my motherland all the way from the United States.
All I wanted is to be
an upright and dignified Chinese.
What the British is doing is too absurd.
If we have to surrender to
this type of shameful request,
how can we still talk about sovereignty and national dignity?
That way we won't even have the most basic human dignity!
Indeed!
This is absurd!
We'll never surrender!
Everybody, listen to me.
To shoulder our responsibilities to Peking University,
can we come up with a sure card
just in case.
Rest assured!
Last night, Shouchang read through
all the references related to this case.
I suggest we listen to him.
Shouchang, please.
Alright.
Dear committee members,
I traced back and referred to the Peking University Education Reform Proposal
Mr. Cai had submitted to Ministry of Education when he took office.
One of stipulations specified that
Peking University has the right to independently decide upon
the employing and discharging of teaching personnel.
This whole proposal was approved by
the then President of the Republic Li Yuanhong,
which means it has legal effect.
Besides, I looked through the approval document
from Ministry of Education with regard to
Peking University forming its appraisal committee.
One of the stipulations stated,
Peking University Appraisal Committee
may base on actual circumstances
dismiss unqualified teaching personnel.
These two should suffice to prove
Cartwright's litigation is complete nonsense.
Shouchang,
I can tell that
you must have stayed up all night yesterday.
But I can assure you that you won't have stayed up for nothing!