[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Five]
The roots of popularising science and democracy
lie in education.
If you, Cai Yuanpei,
can use the treasure of Peking University to reform and innovate
in order to revive our Chinese nation,
you will have our support and hope.
The words of Brother Bo Tang
are exactly what I, Cai Yuanpei, want.
Okay, I'm going to reply to Li Yuanhong
to take up his post at Peking University as soon as possible.
Hold on, Brother Jie Min.
If you want this job, you have to do it right.
It's hard to get there without water (?)
if you want to be in the wrong place of Peking University,
and make a career out of it.
It's going to take a lot of work!
Please teach me, Brother Bo Tang.
I know you have a well-developed idea
of how to revolutionize education,
but in order to achieve your ambition,
you have to meet the conditions set by Li Yuanhong:
sufficient funds,
abundance of talented people,
transfer of power to lower level.
Without these three demands,
your plans will be as good
as the old Beijing saying goes
"a harmful delay".
I have Brother Bo Tang to help Yuanpei.
I will be the president of Peking University.
Good.
Excellent, excellent!
[Yadong Library, Shanghai]
The young are promising!
This Hu Shizhi fired eight shells at once,
each hitting the lifeblood of old literature.
Baisha, hurry up and arrange
the official 1917 New Year's publication
[Yi Baisha, styled Yue Cun, scholar of the New Culture Movement]
[Wang Mengzou, manager of Yadong Library]
of "New Youth" to China
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhong Fu, editor-in-chief of "New Youth"]
as a New Year's gift.
Zhong Fu, take it easy, don't rush.
Didn't we agree?
The first issue will publish Hu Shi's eight vernacular poems.
You can't make it a special issue.
Besides, he's a nobody,
few people in China know him.
If he does not buy it, we can not afford to pay.
Take back that poetic rant. (?)
This article "Urgent discussion on literary improvement" is more influential.
What improved?
Isn't it a revolution?
This influence is a lot bigger.
Is this boy scared?