[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Eleven]
Now that we're back,
you shall know the difference.
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhongfu, Dean of Liberal Arts at Peking University]
Mr. Gu,
[Hu Shi, styled Shizhi, Professor at Peking University]
This statement is also what I wish to deliver to you.
[Liu Shipei, styled Shenshu, Professor at Peking University] [Gu Hongming, styled Tangsheng, Professor at Peking University] This statement...
is what I wish to deliver to everyone sitting here as well.
This is a statement from us at Peking University
towards an outdated China,
an outdated culture.
And it is also a solemn statement of commitment
to the successful future of Peking University!
Dear seniors,
dear faculty members,
dear students,
Mr. Cai just asked:
"How would Peking University cope with such chaotic times?"
This is indeed the very question that we should
contemplate with all our hearts and minds.
I remember in January of 1915.
I talked to Zhu Kezhen (famous geologist and meteorologist) about
our strong urge to establish prestigious universities within China.
Later, I also talked to English teacher Yazhou about
the shame that we didn't have reputable universities.
In the dairy I wrote that day,
I expressed my sincerest hope that
if one day, within China,
there exists a distinguished university,
comparable to Harvard in the U.S.,
Oxford and Cambridge in the U.K.,
University of Berlin in Germany,
or University of Paris in France,
I'd be able to die without regrets.
The next day I still was pondering upon the same issue.
I wrote in my diary,
the absence of national universities,
national libraries,
national museums,
national art gallaries,
should all be regarded as disgraces of a nation.
Today, I'm back eventually.
Me, Hu Shi, has no other extravagant hopes other than
devoting my humble speech
my diligent words
to the course of Peking University
in becoming one of the most esteemed universities in the world!
Hi, have you seen Liu Haiwei and Fu Sinian somewhere?
They're over near the public notice board.
Just over there.
Great, thanks!
Take one! Come one, take one!
They should not stay at Peking University anymore.
Dear students, we strongly urge the university to
expel Gu Hongming,
who aided Zhang Xun's restoration.
That's right! We agree!
We cannot allow Peking University to become
a refuge for the remnants of Feudalist Qing Empire.
Yes, exactly!
We're already the Republic of China.
People like Gu Hongming,
Can never stay here!
Sinian, Haiwei,
I finally found you guys!
Guo,
Mr. Cai is hosting the meeting
for the school's appraisal committee members
Let's go find Mr. Cai.
Alright.
Students, let's all go talk to Mr. Cai!
Sure, let's go.
Sure, sure!
Let's all go together!
Go...
Hurry...
Dear appraisal committee members,
the meeting we have today...
Mr. Cai.
Mr. Cai, we have some request to seek your opinion.
Wait a moment, the faculties are having a meeting right now.
We'd like to meet with Mr. Cai.
Students, please do not interrupt the meeting.
Be quiet.
We're not trying to cause any trouble, sir.
We're exercising our rights
as per Mr. Cai's earlier appeal.
Indeed!
You have no right to stop us from seeing Mr. Cai.
You have no right...
As you can see...
Dean Chen Duxiu, please sit down.
Please excuse me for a second, I'll go take a look.
Mr. Cai is here!
Greetings, Mr. Cai!
Dear fellow students,
What requests do you have? Please let me know.
Mr. Cai, we'd like you to dismiss
the accomplice of Zhang Sun -- Gu Hongming.
Right! Drive him out of Peking University!
Do you have any concrete evidences of
Gu Hongming colluding with Zhang Xun's Restoration?
Sir, the newspaper said so!
Yes, we've read it from the newspaper.
Exactly, we've all seen it!
In conducting scholarly research, we shouldn't parroting others' words.
This is the Peking University academic discipline I have repeatedly emphasized.
I know what's on your mind.
I'm aware of your opinions.
However, your petition has to
go through the formal decision making process of the school's appraisal committee.
My individual words won't count.
What I can do though is to reliably
deliver your petition
to the appraisal committee.
So please go back to your studies for now.
Is that alright?
Mr. Cai, in that case, we request to observe the meeting.
Yes.
Indeed, we wish to observe.
Please allow us to observe.
Huh, this is unheard of!
But even for this matter,
it still has to be approved by the committee.
Please wait here for a bit.
Alright.
Sounds good, Sir.
Thank you, Sir.
I assume you have heard everything.
Please express your views.
How can we allow this?
Having students participate school committee meeting,
This is not appropriate.
What would it bring to the dignity of the school (faculties)?
We can absolutely not set a precedent!
Once a bad example is set,
there will be the second, third time.
again and again...
How can we deal with that?
Dr. Hu Shi, what's your opinion on this?
Dear committee members,
In order to reflect the authority
of our school appraisal committee,
we can invite students to observe.
In order to demonstrate the academic rigor and discipline
of our meeting,
We can ask the students
to select 2 to 3 representatives among themselves
to be the observers.
The rest of them can go back to classes.
I agree with Dr. Hu.
I agree.
I think Dr. Hu's suggestion is brilliant.
Okay, let's follow Dr. Hu's advice.
Guo,
Please have 2 to 3 representatives among yourselves to observe the meeting.
Is that okay?
Sure!
Let's make a decision.
How about you three?
Why not.
We'll wait for the good news from you guys.
Sir,
We're the 3 representatives elected.
Great, let's welcome the 3 non-voting delegates.
Thank you, sir.
The rest of you, please go back first.
Thank you and goodbye, sir.
Let's go.
Let's go then.
Mr. Cai.
Alright,
according to the students' request,
we're going to discuss whether or not
we should dismiss Prof. Gu Hongming.
Please express your own views.
He's extremely knowledgeable (in his field).
We do need to make this decision carefully.
Dean Chen,
Since this is mostly a matter within Liberal Arts,
Would you talk about it first?
With regard to whether
Gu Hongming is adequate for the professorship,
within Liberal Arts, we do have two apposing views.
On one hand, some believe that
Gu Hongming participated in Zhang Xun's Restoration,
which brought disgrace to the teachers. Therefore should be dismissed.
On the other hand, others maintain that
The hiring of professors should rely upon their teaching credentials
rather than whether or not they support the restoration.
We have surveyed our faculty members,
and found out that roughly same number of people were on each side.
Therefore, this time, we didn't list
Gu Hongming among personnel to be dismissed.
Mr. Cai,
and dear colleagues,
I wish to vouch for Gu Hongming.
As far as I know,
Gu was dragged along to the performance by Zhang Xun.
He had no idea of the Restoration beforehand.
Even though, he did meet the "empire" at the palace,
as for appointing him to be the Administer of Foreign Affairs,
that's complete rumor.
When he came to complain to me a couple of days ago,
he was full of regrets and grievances.
He's in his 60s now.
And he has a bunch of costly problems and habits.
If we're to take away his incomes,
it's equivalent to killing him.
I think we'd better show some leniency and let him off.
[Qian Xuantong, styled Deqian, Professor at Peking University] Gu supports the Monarchy,
and brings disgrace to us teachers.
Why should we still keep people like this?
Let's kick him out!
Yes, I agree!
How can we kick him out?
The key to Gu's matter,
is to determine whether he used the Peking University classrooms
to incite students to support the Restoration and oppose the Republic.
If that's not the case, we have no reason to dismiss him.
Facts speak louder than words!
Gu dishonored scholarship!
Gu is indeed supporting the Restoration!
Isn't that true?
We cannot dismiss him.
He did do that.
Let's listen to Mr. Cai.
Please sit down.
Our student delegates.
May I ask if you have any evidences (of Gu supporting the Restoration)?
Sir, we don't.
Okay, please sit down.
But, when Gu gives his lectures here,
Nobody wants to attend.
The British Poetry course he teaches,
only covers 6 poems and a few stanzas.
Typically, only 1 to 2 students would show up to his lectures.
Dear teachers, there're 365 days in a year,
but he only teaches 6 poems plus a dozen of lines.
How many words would that be?
If we do the maths, students probably are not even learning one word per day!
How can there be people as lazy as this!
This is wasting students time.
We have to kick him out!
Aye! Aye!
Wasting students' time!
I agree!
Alright, it seems clear now.
Gu Hongming has issues regarding his teaching credentials.
I petition the committee
to allow me to give Gu Hongming
a disciplinary counseling.
Let's give him a month.
Within a month,
If students are still willing to attend his lectures,
then we continue to hire him.
If students are not acknowledging his effort,
then we dismiss him.
Would you all agree?
Agreed.
Now that we resolved this issue,
our 3 student delegates, please feel free to leave.
We're to discuss the next item on our meeting.
Sing Peking Opera "First drum, prepare battle food"
"Second drum, tighten the armor"
"Third drum, knife out of sheath"
"Fourth drum, be at war"
"The ones marched forward all get rewarded"
"The ones backed off inevitably injured"
"The three armies returned to the camp with the commander"
"The famous general Lian Po"
"Is he still strong and intrepid, despite his age?"
Master, you look worried.
Liu Er,
how many years have you served me?
Ever since Puyi abdicated,
if it was not you master, who took me in,
where else would I end up?
If I can no longer stay at Peking University,
where else can you go?
Mater, what are you talking about?
I'm in the twilight of my life...
I don't really care about where I may end up.
Not to mention, I owe you a debt of gratitude for your recognition.
Mater, wherever you go,
me, Liu Er, would go too.
San Er.
Mater.
Prepare the sedan, I'll go get some Southern pastries from Daoxiangcun (Famous Pastry shop in Beijing).
Master, you can just hand over this type of errands to me.
No, I insist on going myself.
Mr. Cai,
Prof. Gu is here.
Please.
My esteemed Mr. Cai,
I'm here to pay my respect to you.
Tangsheng, there you are.
Why did you bring these?
I know that Mr. Cai is from the South,
and misses Southern food.
So I went to Daoxiangcun by myself today,
and brought you some pastries from Jiahu.
Please give them a try.
Brother Tangsheng, you didn't have to do this.
I know that you are not well-off yourself.
Not to mention you are a big spender.
Please accept my gratitude, Brother Tangsheng.
You're too polite.
Please come over and sit down.
No need,
No need to trouble you.
I brought my own tea.
Well, please sit down then.
Tangsheng.
This is the first-class tea from my hometown.
Please give it a taste.
Thank you, thank you.
Please sit.
Thank you.
Tangsheng, I should have gone to your place
to pay you a visit.
It's all because I was too caught up
in the affairs of the university.
That's why I invited you to come here instead.
I'm now talking to you on behalf of
the school appraisal committee.
Please go ahead, Mr. Cai.
Tangsheng, let me ask you this:
If you're to leave Peking University,
would you be willing?
No, I won't.
Of course I won't.
Why?
Mr. Cai, our nation is plunged in chaos.
I, Gu Hongming,
have nowhere else to turn to except Peking University.
In that case,
please don't take what I'm about to say as mere threats.
I'd really appreciate that you think it over carefully and seriously.
I'm all ears.
The university's top priority for now,
is to recruit talents from all parts of the nation,
and to dismiss disqualified mediocrities.
This is the key point of our conversation.
As for you Gu Tangsheng,
there're loads of controversies around you both within and outside of our campus.
The petition for terminating your contract,
is now supported by many.
May I ask you, Mr. Cai,
Do you consider me, Hongming, as a disqualified mediocrity?
Mediocrity -- not necessarily.
But, as for being disqualified, we do have solid proof.