[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Four]
[Qianmen Street, Beijing]
[Li Dazhao, styled Shou Chang, editor-in-chief of the "Morning Bell"]
Where do you live, brother?
Outside Yondingmen, as a pariah.
Why do you say this?
Those who pull carts, wield skill in trade
have shaved heads, are pig butchers, coffin carriers,
all live over there.
Then how is getting by in life right now for you guys?
Impossible to get by. Everyone's suffering until they can't take it anymore.
According to the older generations' saying,
we have never gone through such sullen days.
Didn't you say that since this President Lai has took office,
he has made a lot of promises?
President Lai!
He only cares about fighting with Duan Qirui for power,
he doesn't care about the lives of the people.
Good people, I'm begging you.
My child has high fever for days now.
I'm begging you.
People are worse than animals.
Brother.
Pull over for a moment.
Good people, I'm begging you.
I'm begging you.
[Zhao Shiyan, styled Qin Sheng, student at The High School Affiliated to Beijing Normal University]
What's wrong with you?
What's going on with this guy?
Go!
[Ge Shugui, worker at Changxindian, Beijing]
This is my daughter-in-law!
You can't do that even if she's your daughter-in-law!
What are you doing here?
What's the point of making a fool of yourself here?
Am I ashamed? Ge Shugui!
If... if I leave, the child will be dead.
We poor people are born to die.
A poor man's life is not a fragile one.
You can't die standing up, you know?
Go!
You go!
I want you to kneel!
Why are you hitting her?
Don't hit her!
I want you to kneel!
What kind of skill is beating someone up?
Yeah!
Brother!
Don't fight. Don't fight.
I said stop fighting!
Don't fight!
I have money.
I have money, you can have it.
I'll see what I can do, brother.
Lend me some money, will you?
Brother, save the child!
Why are you still kneeling?
Save the child!
Lend some money, brother.
Lend me some money.
Sister, sister.
Save the child, save the children.
Lend me some money.
Sister, sister.
Have pity on the child.
Sister-in-law, take the children with you.
I'll take you to the doctor.
Get up.
Pull the cart over.
Got it!
Go now, go.
Mister!
Mister! Thank you!
Get up! Quickly, get up!
Quickly, get up! Up!
Get up!
Student.
Which hospital is closest to here?
The French hospital.
The French hospital!
Come on, I'll take you there.
Alright.
Come, come, come.
Make way, make way.
Come on, slow down.
Be careful.
Go.
Why are you still standing there?
Come on, go!
Go!
Aiya... I'm so angry!
Your great kindness, mister.
Get up.
I can't repay you.
If you need me in the future, just ask.
You don't have to be so polite.
Let's get to know each other.
My name is Li Dazhao.
Just arrived in Beijing to run a newspaper.
You are Mr. Li Shou Chang.
I have read your book.
I admire you.
Student, I admire you too.
How do I call you?
My name is Zhao Shiyan.
A student at The High School Affiliated to Beijing Normal University.
My name is Ge Shugui, a worker from Changxingdian.
What do you do as a worker?
Locomotive repair.
Good.
I've just arrived in Beijing and I don't know my way around.
Let's be friends.
I can't afford that.
Equality for all.
There is no distinction between high and low culture.
Sir, how can I be like you?
Look at what you're saying, I can't even answer.
You can't say that.
The tough talk on the street just now
had us all in stitches.
Right.
Brother Ge is a man with a backbone.
It's coming.
How's it going?
Son.
Doctor.
Doctor, how is my son?
Needs hospitalisation.
hospitalisation.
It's so serious!
Don't worry, it's not life-threatening.
You guys go ahead and check in.
How much does it cost to get admitted to hospital.
Around thirty dollars or so.
Baby will protect you.
Shugui.
Follow me.
I cannot accept.
I cannot accept, Mr. Dazhao!
For your willingness to help us,
we are already very grateful.
How can we ask you to sell something?
We should do it ourselves!
Do you need to go out on the street if you've got what it takes?
Don't worry, these things don't get in the way of life.
Come.
Short sleeves with missing lapels, few buttons and no buttons,
a protective cover each with an open bottom,
and a pair of leather shoes.
Two silver dollars.
No, it won't work!
Mr. Dazhao, you can't use this.
You can't! You can't!
And this.
Worn out, wrong time,
one old pocket watch.
Four silver dollars in total when sold.
Sold.
I don't regret doing this.
Short sleeves with missing lapels, few buttons and no buttons,
a protective cover each with an open bottom,
and a pair of leather shoes.
Worn out, wrong time,
one old pocket watch.
I don't regret doing this.
Shugui, come with me somewhere.
[Editorial board of the "Morning Bell"]
Come on, come on. Higher.
Higher, higher. Balance on both sides.
Wait for me here.
Good. Nailed it.
Lao Xie.
Mr. Shou Chang! Welcome, welcome.
Just about to go to the station.
No more pleasantries for now.
Lend me thirty dollars quickly.
I have a friend who has a family emergency.
You lend it to me
and just take it out of my salary next month.
OK.
Xiang Li!
Go and get thirty silver dollars.
Alright, alright.
Hurry up.
How's your health?
Same as always, OK.
You caught me off guard.
You see, the welcome ceremony is being set up for you.
Good.
Here.
Shugui.
Thirty dollars.
Brother Ge.
As you said, poor people don't have a fragile life.
Save a life, quickly!
Lao Xie.
You'll also have to lend me ten dollars.
I need to get my stuff
back from the pawnshop.
Hurry up, hurry up and get it.
Good trip. How are you?
Come on, big guy.
We warmly welcome
editor-in-chief Li Dazhao, who has returned from Japan.
Good!
Hello.
Student, take a look and see!
[Aurora College, Shanghai]
This issue of the "New Youth"
especially "Youth" by Mr. Li Dazhao
is the most exciting.
Let me read you a paragraph:
"To advance civilisation for the world,"
"to create happiness for mankind,"
"with our youthful selves,"
"to create a youthful family,"
"a youthful nation,"
"a youthful people,"
"a youthful humanity,"
"a youthful earth,"
"a youthful universe..."
Sorry about that!
Who's there?
Did you see if there's anyone up here?
It's her!
The one with the accordion at the back!
That's me.
Did you see anyone down here?
What's going on?
It's wet. The magazines are wet.
I was in a hurry to get to class and didn't see them.
How about this,
I'll give you ten dollars.
You catch!
What an attitude!
Who are you shouting at?
What's wrong with me yelling at you?
Get down here!
Then you wait there.
God there are people like this.
Brother, I'm all wet.
Who are you shouting at?
Do you know what you've done wrong?
Whoever you are, you've drenched the magazine
and you haven't even said you're sorry.
I've given you the money.
I've just made it very clear.
I was in a hurry to get to class, I didn't see it.
I was just up there, I couldn't get down.
What more do you want from me?
Do you give money like that?
I don't mean your money.
It's as much as it should be.
Qiaonian, how many copies?
What's your attitude?
With a woman like you scattering flowers in the sky
and throwing money away?
Thirteen copies.
Twenty-two cents per copy.
How much money?
Two dollars and eighty-six cents.
Add to that the word "Sorry".
I've given you ten dollars.
You can pay for all your magazines for ten dollars.
Ten dollars will get you both a lot of food.
Who wants to go out for dinner on your dime?
Do you have any manners
and are you reasonable?
Did your family ever teach you
the rules?
Rules, huh?
Then I'll give you a good lecture on the rules today.
This is a school.
You have broken a school rule.
The school rule is
that no one is allowed to set up a stall here.
You've set up a stall and you're in breach of school rules.
I'm still really surprised.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
I suddenly remembered that I hadn't met you guys before.
Sister, how did you get here?
Sister, we are new students.
New students, are you?
New students are expected to follow the school rules.
The new students don't study hard,
they just set up shop and do business here
which will delay their studies.
How can you live up to the parents who provide for you?
Who doesn't study well anymore?
We call this work-study after school.
French class is a preparatory class for work-study in France.
Then we can work-study in France
but not in our own country.
What's the point?
Work-study?
That's a trendy way of putting it.
There are rules everywhere in China.
School rules are school rules.
Yes, we are new students
and we don't know the rules.
But now that we know
we can walk
but before that happens, you have to say one word to us.
"Sorry"
We'll leave as soon as we've finished.
I've grown up
and never said that word.
Are you leaving?
I'm not leaving.
OK.
Supervisor!
Sister, don't!
Don't stop her. Let her shout.
Sister, don't shout.
Shout!
Supervisor!
Sister, don't shout.
We are not like the others.
The "New Youth" magazine is an emancipator of the mind!
[Chen Qiaonian, second son of Chen Duxiu]
Do you know Mr. Li Dazhao?
I don't know Li Dazhao.
You leaving?
Not leaving.
OK, hold this for me.
Don't do this.
Not leaving, are you?
I'll do it.
Sister!
What are you doing? You want to go insane?
I didn't ask for trouble.
The students are watching
while I reasoned with her.
I'm not being a jerk.
Put the magazines down.
You're a stubborn person.
There's no reasoning with you!
Why do you have no sense at all?
Sister, don't take our things!
Have a good talk!
You give me back the magazine!
Sister!
Make way!
Brother, let's sell it somewhere else.
Don't sell it here.
Alright.
Sell it there and nowhere else.
Here you go.
Thank you.
Grandpa,
I'll set up a stall here
to sell "New Youth" magazines.
What?
I want a stall here selling magazines,
is it a concern for you?
Selling books.
What book?
"New Youth"
Sell it, sell it.
Thank you!
To love or not to love.
It's not easy to watch them.
They are the ones who work and study.
Let's all disperse and get on with it.
Close the door.
Take a look and see!
Don't miss it passing by!
"New Youth", just published!
See Mr. Li Dazhao's "Youth"!
See the newly published "New Youth"!
Young man, how much is the magazine?
Hello, twenty-two cents a copy.
Come and have a look.
I'll take a look.
Yes, I'll take one.
Twenty-two cents.
That's it. Thank you.
Have a good read. Qianian, receipt!
OK.
"New Youth"!
Hello.
How much is "New Youth"?
Twenty-two cents a copy.
I'll take one.
Take a look.
That's it. Thank you.
Hello, have a look at the "New Youth".
Qiaonian!
Two copies!
Come, take a look!
See Mr. Li Dazhao's "Youth"!
See the newly published "New Youth"!
Thank you!
Brother, I've got one here too.
Don't mess it up.
"New Youth"!
See Mr. Li Dazhao's "Youth"!
This is a well written paragraph.
Stop, stop, stop.
See Mr. Li Dazhao's "Youth"!
See the newly published "New Youth"!
Young man.
Let me ask you something.
Do you have
the newly reissued issue
of the magazine that published
Li Dazhao's "Youth"?
We have, we have.