[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Fifteen]
Come, come, come.
My humble home is honored by your presence.
Brother Qinnan, you're too polite.
May I ask brother Qinnan,
how many kinds of published translated works do you have?
[Gu Hongming, born Tangsheng, Professor at Peking University]
About more than 180 kinds.
Among these, there are more than 40 kinds of world masterpieces.
A great expert!
It's not that I'm speaking highly of you.
When it comes to translators,
it could be said that you are China's foremost.
Mr. Tangsheng, you overpraise!
Compared to Mr. Tangsheng,
I'm no more than a scholar.
[Lin Shu, styled Qinnan]
Honorable Qinnan, you are really too modest.
Brother Qinnan, speaking of which,
we are both of the same profession.
You take Western classics and translate them into the Chinese language.
I take Chinese classics and translate them into foreign languages.
Different methods, but same results.
What New Culture does this Hu Shi and Chen Duxiu advocate?
What do they know about New Culture?
If I were saying it,
only when Lin Qinnan and I, Gu Hongming, are together,
is it really New Culture.
Only the distinguished can follow the correct path.
Beloved mentor.
This Zhang Changli is my student,
strongly committed to preserving national heritage.
Right now, he is a member of the National Assembly
and is preparing to submit a proposal to the National Assembly
to revive state religion.
It's an honor to meet you at last.
This young Zhang Fengzai is Legislator Zhang's nephew
and also, when I was in Wucheng Middle School,
my student when I was teaching.
He is now a student of Chinese studies in Peking University
and also working part-time at "Shenzhou Daily" as a journalist.
Today, I requested everyone to come
to talk over a matter.
Chen Duxiu of Anhui advocated for smashing Kong's family business (=Confucianism, pejorative)
to engage in affairs like vernacular Chinese, vernacular poetry
and the so-called New Culture Movement.
It hasn't been only one or two days now.
Since this year,
these people think Peking University is a stronghold,
[Liu Shipei, styled Shenshu, Professor at Peking University]
seriously harming traditional Chinese studies.
I know everyone here are masters of Chinese studies
who have long and bitterly detested these people.
Rotten old me is untalented.
In my early years, I once accompanied the respected mentor Wu Rulun
to establish the Imperial University of Peking,
and I really cannot bear to see the downfall of Peking University and national heritage.
A few days ago, I sent a letter to Cai Yuanpei,
raising questions.
Cai replied to me,
saying that I was welcome to wait for Peking University to give a lecture or publish a magazine
[Huang Kan, styled Jigang, Professor at Peking University]
to launch an academic debate.
Today I requested a group of virtuous people to come
to seek everyone's enlightening remarks
whether to meet with them in debate.
I dare ask brother Qinnan,
what is the purpose of this?
Dissatisfied sirs. For all my life, rotten me have engaged in studies,
advocating the Tongcheng School of Neo-Confucianism.
Being subjects, we can only vow loyalty to the Great Qing Emperor.
When I was ten, I visited the Guangxu Emperor's tomb
to recover my faith in the Great Qing's legitimacy,
to rectify and recover my belief in the Three Fundamental Bonds of Confucianism.
If it's for reinstating Great Qing's legitimacy
to rectify and recover the Three Fundamental Bonds of Confucianism,
I, Gu Hongming, am duty-bound.
But if it's to overturn Mr. Cai Yuanpei,
I beg to differ.
Moreover, I firmly oppose.
I hold the same view with the Honorable Tang.
I approve of restoring the ancient ways and the imperial monarchy
but I will never oppose Cai Yuanpei and Chen Duxiu.
My standpoint is different.
I approve of returning to the old ways
but I oppose reinstating the imperial monarchy,
I even more oppose Chen Duxiu and that Hu Shi.
No matter what is said,
returning to the old ways is our common ground.
Then we shall seek the Great Harmony while reserving our differences.
How about that?
Agreed.
Good. Then let's discuss
what we are going to do for magazines and lectures
to confront them with.
Also, please give us an idea
of what Legislator Zhang's proposal to reinstate the old ways specifically mentions,
and also I request everyone to give out some ideas.
Beloved mentor, little nephew Zhang Fengzai got a hold of some of
Peking University's new developments.
Is it possible to allow him to give the great masters a little introduction?
Okay.
Know yourself, know your enemies. Only then can you win every fight.
Gentlemen. Peking University have posted notices.
Starting from next week,
a series of lectures on New Culture
with the theme of vernacular Chinese will be held.
These are the lecture subjects and list of lecturers.
Bring it over, I'll take a look.
Good. Cai Yuanpei
is even going up on stage.
This Lu Xun is that
Zhou Shuren who wrote "A Madman's Diary".
Precisely.
The influence of this novel
is endlessly wicked.
"The Danzi people are like birds and beasts,
How could we be of the same herd?"
I actually propose to the Honorable Qinnan,
we need to go to Peking University to watch
and listen to their lectures
to understand what they are selling in the end.
After that,
we take the appropriate steps.
Good. Then would you please notify Cai Yuanpei,
I want to go to Peking University to hear the lectures.
In this era of literary innovation,
All aristocratic literature, classical literature
and Shanlin literature
(pastoral literature, lit. mountain literature)
are equally rejected.
Why?
These three types of literature,
our present exaggerated flattery,
hypocrisy and profanity
are interdependent.
Therefore, if we want to reform politics today,
we have to first reform
the literature that has been entrenched in the political spirit.
Ladies and gentlemen, where did modern European civilization originate?
It originated from the Renaissance.
In the future, where will our cultural prosperity originate?
I'll be as bold as to predict
it certainly has its origins in today's literary revolution.
Good!
Very arrogant.
Gentlemen!
Students!
I very much approve of Mr. Zhongfu's speech.
Next, I want to say a few sentences from my heart.
My viewpoint is clear.
If China wants to develop, then we must abolish Chinese characters.
Arrogant.
Everybody, keep calm.
Listen to me talk about the reason.
Every civilization, every nation's written language on Earth
have experienced the transition of characters coming from shapes
to ideographical characters
to phonetic characters in this evolutionary process.
Phonetic characters, such as in the Latin alphabet,
represents a
higher stage in the evolution of written language.
Chinese characters are not phonetic,
but rather are characters that represent shape and meaning.
As a result, we have to abolish it.
You are talking rubbish!
Mr. Qian,
if Chinese characters are abolished, then what do we use?
Yeah. What do we use?
Good question!
Writing
is nothing more than a language of symbolizing objects.
We should adopt a written language of fully simple grammar
with neat pronunciation, and of excellent quality.
Esperanto.
It is the international language.
Why don't we use our own culture?
Not using our own culture!
Professor Qian,
I think your point of view is truly absurd.
Yeah! Absurd!
If we follow Professor Qian's argument,
my understanding is
to have all of us Chinese people
learn anew a language from a foreign country.
Why can't it be?
I think he is not doing New Culture
he is destroying culture!
Even more so wants to destroy my race!
Right!
Brother Xingyan!
If we don't apply fierce medicine, then how is China going to move forward?
Forgetting one's roots!
Beat him to death!
I must insist on my own point of view!
This is my opinion!
Those of you sitting, which one of you isn't Chinese.
I am also Chinese.
I love my country.
I believe, in order to carry out New Culture,
we need to start from abolishing Chinese characters.
Qian Xuantong!
My vast China
with 5000 years of Chinese history,
how can the characters that the ancestors left behind be abolished?
You forget your roots! You advocate for national chaos and bad habits!
Yeah!
Chen Zhongfu!
Qian Xuantong is your "New Youth"'s
fellow editor.
Is abolishing Chinese characters
the result you want from New Culture?
You must give a statement.
Right! Give a statement!
Give a statement!
I can very much understand
Professor Qian's argument for abolishing Chinese characters,
through a heart concerned for Chinese culture.
But,
regarding the decision to abolish Chinese characters,
I don't agree with it at all.
So, I refrain from saying my opinions.
A punishable heart!
Talking rubbish!
We must strike back.
We must absolutely not allow them to recklessly act like this.
Let me see. I'll take the lead.
Give Hu Shi, that child, a show of strength.
Everyone says that Mr. Hu Shi has charm with women.
Look, so many people came.
Seeing it today, sure enough a justified reputation.
Did you guys know?
His young wife is a footbound peasant woman
who can't understand classical Chinese.
That can't be?
I only just heard it before.
Isn't his young wife a girl from a wealthy family who could read?
I also heard this. Isn't it?
He's here!
Mr. Shizhi is here!
Ladies.
Gentlemen.
Happy spring.
Happy spring!
Today's topic I'm speaking about is
"Vernacular Chinese and Vernacular Poetry".
Lots of friends ask me
why do you, Hu Shi, insist on advocating for vernacular Chinese
and abandon the tradition of classical Chinese.
My answer is:
first, classical Chinese of those days
is a kind of half-dead kind of writing.
Ordinary people are unable to understand what they see, even less what they hear.
Second, the vernacular Chinese we are advocating today
is a kind of living writing,
not at all vulgar.
Third, vernacular is not only not vulgar
it is also very elegant and practical.
Because vernacular
is a kind of very expressful language.
We know
expressing meaning is a language's main function.
Language that doesn't express is not beautiful.
For example,
in Mr. Lu Xun's novel "A Madman's Diary"
there is such a passage like this,
Old man Zhao turned around and fell down on the street,
flopped and kowtowed three times.
This section is simple, lively, graceful and vivid.
It would be hard to attain this in Classical Chinese.
I don't know
if everyone here agrees with me.
Agree!
Agree! Good!
Good!
Forgive me for begging to differ with
Professor Hu's point of view.
I hear that Professor Hu Shi just said
that comparing vernacular Chinese to classical Chinese is just simplifying the complicated
to have something more convenient fast, and effective.
This is not true.