[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Eight]
Dean Chen,
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhongfu, Dean of Liberal Arts at Peking University]
you are the flag carrier of new culture.
[Cai Yuanpei, styled Jiemin, President of Peking University]
What do you think, amongst those present today,
[Gu Hongming, (?) Tangsheng, Professor at Peking University]
who, because they venerate Confucius,
are without virtue?
I've never thought those who venerate Confucius are without virtue.
There are two kinds of people who venerate Confucius.
Those who are academic Confucians.
[Qian Xuantong, styled Deqian, Professor at Peking University]
And those who are political Confucians.
The discipline of Confucianism
was originally one school of thought out of the hundred
from the Spring and Autumn period.
One field of knowledge.
It is wide-ranging and profound, long-standing and well-established.
This is my passion for Chinese culture.
It should be respected.
Peking University is the flagship institution of higher learning in China.
Teaching and studying Confucianism is the right thing to do.
Therefore, I have no objection.
People who have studied Confucius will be professors at Peking University.
Dean Chen.
I've heard a lot about Dean Chen.
He is a person who is frank on the outside as he is inside.
But today it's a bit of a misnomer.
"Smash Kong family's business!"
(pejorative term for Confucianism)
is your, editor-in-chief's, "New Youth"'s
erected banner.
And under your command,
such as Yi Baisha in Hunan,
Wu Yu from Sichuan,
and Li Dazhao in Beijing,
Qian Xuantong of Peking University,
are all your daring vanguard.
On their bodies. (?)
There is no trace of respect for Confucius
and for Confucianism.
Not even a trace!
Not even a stitch!
How stitchless!
Professor Gu can enjoy reading
our "New Youth".
It is a great honor for me.
But Professor Gu doesn't seem to understand it very well.
This "New Youth" proposed to smash Kong family's business
It is not Confucius nor Confucianism.
It is the Three Fundamental Bonds and Five Constant Virtues of Confucianism.
What we oppose is political respect for Confucius,
not academic respect for Confucius.
As we all know, Dong Zhongshu dismissed hundreds,
he has respected Confucianism alone.
This Confucius and Confucianism changed its form.
It became a weapon for the emperors to rule the country
and oppress the people.
As the saying goes, "ruler and subject,
father and son,
husband and wife".
It has choked the vitality of the country.
It has harmed the lives of the people.
It has hindered the progress of civilization.
In a word, it has caused the backwardness of China.
Shouldn't these Three Fundamental Bonds of Confucianism
be smashed?
Aye.
Well said, well said.
Dean Chen is really a master of argumentation.
Confucius has been gone for more than two thousand years.
What does he have to do with our politics today?
For the backwardness of China today,
[Huang Kan, styled Jigang, Professor at Peking University]
should Old Master Kong be responsible?
Mr. Huang Kan, sit down and talk.
Dean Chen is too good at arguing.
Yes.
Yuan Shikai's restoration of the monarchy, in order to become emperor,
means worshiping Confucius's doctrine as the state religion,
and respecting Confucianism as the national school of thought.
This is the politics at hand.
Confucian feudal ethics to this day
still dominate social life,
enslaving the people's thoughts.
Isn't this the reason why China is backward?
Zhongfu, Zhongfu.
You're going a bit too far.
Your views
can be presented on the podium of Peking University.
What I'm asking you now is
that do you, as Dean of Liberal Arts,
agree that
academic level
is an important criterion
for our appointment of liberal arts professors at Peking University?
Master Cai, with all due respect,
I don't want to give a speech, but it always annoy me,
Mr. Cai.
Forgive me for not being able to agree with you just now.
A Peking University professor.
The first criterion should be the teacher's morality.
If you are not virtuous enough,
you can't be a professor at Peking University no matter how good you are.
Professors are teachers.
We can't have a bad person
to set an example for students.
Right.
Yeah, that's right.
This Mr. Zhongfu.
You are a little too melodramatic here.
Then tell me
which one of you is a bad person
Because Gu Tangsheng is not in favor of new culture,
is he a bad person?
Speak!
Right.
Master Cai, don't get me wrong.
I never said Professor Gu was a bad person.
That's why I put him
on the list of reappointed professors.
But now that we're here,
I will then also tell you all frankly
that some people have put it forward,
many people have put it forward.
Peking University can't be regarded as
the umbrella of the royalist party.
Chen Zhongfu!
Make it clear!
Who is the umbrella?
Who is the royalist party? Speak!
Who is the royalist party?
Who is the umbrella?
Mr. Huang Kan, sit down and talk.
I won't sit down!
What I said is my opinion!
I, Qian Xuantong, just don't associate with buffoons.