[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Three]
"Friends wanted:"
"From '28 Strokes Student'"
"Commoner student from Changsha"
[Chen Chang: student at Hunan First Normal School]
"who can endure hardships and toil"
"to serve the nation with unstinting selflessness."
"Is in search of:"
"Fellow travellers"
"From far and wide."
"Which is to say, seeking friends"
"Like a bird screaming for assistance."
How novel!
Even the classifieds can be used to make friends.
Are we helping this '28 Strokes Student'
find a wife?
Mr. Yu Heng.
Foreign persimmons
Here, try it.
[He Shuheng: student at Hunan First Normal School]
You too.
You've misunderstood
this classmate.
He is
looking for a friend
with the same common purpose of serving the country.
How grand.
You all
seem to be making a pact of brotherhood.
[Cai Hesen's mother, Ge Jianhao]
Who is this '28 Strokes Student'?
Ma, '28 Strokes Student'
is Mao Zedong.
You know, Runzhi.
Oh, Runzhi.
That kid is something!
[Li Lisan: student at Hunan First Normal School]
Excuse me,
Which one of you is '28 Strokes Student'?
[Xiao Zisheng: student at Hunan First Normal School]
Hello, hello.
I am here to apply for the meeting of friends.
My name is Cai Hesen.
How do you do?
This is Xiao Zisheng.
My hands are covered with ink.
Chen Chang.
Hello.
This one, this is He Shuheng.
How do you do.
And '28 Strokes Student' is...
He'll be right back.
Eat first.
Ok.
I've found a treasure! I've found a treasure!
28 Strokes Student is back.
Mother Ge.
You've worked hard.
Runzhi,
What are you talking about?
"Sent to the foothills"
"Hidden in the famous mountains"
Ah, right.
From "The Book of Documents"
"Sent to the foothills"
"Though he is late because of thunder and rain, he is not lost."
28 Strokes Student,
I believe,
the Heavens is about to confer a great responsibility.
Runzhi, a new friend.
"Whoever rescues the nation"
"Is considered a kindred spirit."
New friend,
what is your name?
You are too kind.
My name is Li Lisan.
[Li Lisan: student at Hunan Guangyi School]
I come from Liling, Hunan.
I am '28 Strokes Student'
Mao Zedong.
Hello. How do you do.
Please sit.
Take a look at my treasure.
Sure.
What treasure?
Come, come, come.
Lend a hand.
Runzhi,
To the side.
Lost your manners?
You'll know it when you see it.
Here.
Look.
This is my treasure.
One for each.
One book a person.
Today,
at our recruitment meeting,
let's discuss this,
and nothing else.
Come, take a look.
Look at this first,
Look, look.
This really is a treasure.
Everyone,
This is Mr. Chen Duxiu's "The Youth Magazine."
Mr. Yang Changji
has already recommended it to us many times.
He says it is the prescription to save the nation.
Run Huan is right.
This is the remedy that will save lives.
I've only
briefly skimmed the founding statement.
Reading
"A Call to the Youth"
I felt as if
I've been struck by a thunderbolt.
Absolutely enlightening!
Runzhi,
You've bought so many issues at once.
How are you going to eat this month?
'Tis enough to have this book.
Runzhi,
don't worry and read your book.
If you do get hungry
come to Mother Ge
and you'll definitely
eat your fill.
Here. Great.
I'm actually hungry.
You've reminded me.
Mother Ge,
remember to make it spicy.
The very spicy kind.
Got it for you.
Thank you!
Everyone,
I'm so energized.
Haven't we always been talking
about creating a new people?
Well, what is the new youth?
Mr. Chen Zhongfu
right here
talks about six criteria.
Be independent, and not servile.
Be progressive, and not conservative.
Be aggressive, and not retiring.
Be cosmopolitan, and not isolationist.
Be utilitarian, and not formalistic.
Be scientific, and not fanciful.
Wonderfully put!
The six criteria proposed by Mr. Zhongfu
is exactly the direction to work towards
for my generation.
True.
These six criteria are good,
but I don't think
they are comprehensive enough.
What do you mean?
I just feel
there needs to be at least one more.
Be sturdy, and not frail.
Tell me more.
Everyone,
our nation's scholars are more often
bookish and frail.
A military spirit has not been encouraged.
Only when the young people boldly striving to save the country
are physically strong,
can their efforts be similarily vigorous.
Then the moniker bestowed on us by foreigners
"the sick man of Asia"
can be actually thrown off completely.
Well said. Makes sense.
I approve.
I approve as well.
Yes, I also agree.
You're getting soaked!
Don't worry.
He's just like this.
Civilized in spirit
With both strength of body and strength of convictions
There's nothing on earth that's impossible.
Everyone,
This is
the new youth of China.
I've thought about it.
I am going to contribute to "Youth Magazine"
and discuss in depth
the physical education of Chinese people.
Good, good.
Like many young students
who struggled to find the truest way to save the country,
Moa Zedong's eyes were opened by the magazine "New Youth."
He started to explore
the ideas of the early New Culture Movement.
During this period,
he wrote these words in his diary:
In struggling with the sky, is there boundless joy.
In struggling with the earth, is there boundless joy.
In struggling with the people, is there boundless joy.
Students,
[Tianjin Nankai Middle School auditorium]
I read
this newly published "Youth Magazine"
and was immediately attracted by the
inaugural address "A Call to Youth" by Mr.Chen Duxiu.
[Zhou Enlai, styled Xiang Yu, Nankai School Student]
It was like a bright lamp
that illuminated my mind,
It made me feel like
everything I've thought and learned and done before
was all for nought.
Therefore, I plan to switch
my oral reading
with this issue of "Youth Magazine"
to share my delight with everyone.
Compariots desiring to leave the age of ignorance,
ashamed of their simple mindedness,
and eager to catch up,
must pay equal attention to scientific knowledge and human rights.
Our scholars do not know science.
So they follow the Naturalists' School of auspicious signs and five elements.
Confusing the world and cheating the people.
Our farmers do not know science.
So they have no methods for seed selection or insecticide.
Our industrialists do not know science.
So goods lie wasted on the ground,
as we are dependent on foreign countries.
Our merchants do not know science.
So they only care about short term profits,
without any thought for planning for the future.
Our physicians do not know science.
So they are not acquainted with human anatomy.
The truth
in the universe is boundless.
The fertile realms of science awaiting the trailblazer
are immense!
Youth, take up the task!
[Shanghai]
Strike your little gong.
"Youth Magazine" has been published.
Chinese society has many difficulties.
Mr. Chen Duxiu has shared two prescriptions with the public.
Mr. Democracy and Mr. Science
has already come to China.
King of steel, Carnegie.
That's Carnegie, not Shmarnegie.
Wonderful! Wonderful!
Turns out he was originally just a working boy.
Great!
Hello, excuse me.
Take a look, take a peek.
"Youth Magazine"
Mr. Democracy and Mr. Science are here.
See how Carnegie fulfilled the American Dream.
How he went from a worker to the king of steel!
Here, take a look.
"Youth Magazine" Come, take a look.
Newest edition.
Take a look.
Together?
Thank you, thank you.
"Youth Magazine"
He's from my hometown.
His name is Hu Shi.
When he was nineteen years old
he went to study abroad in the US,
first at Cornell University to study agricultural science,
then he switched his major to literature.
He went to Columbia University this year
to study with that well-known professor, John Dewey,
for a doctorate of philosophy.
It can be said that this child
is proficient in literature, history, and philosophy.
He saw an issue of our "Youth Magazine"
[Yi Baisha, styled Yue Cun, New Culture Movement activist]
and was very excited.
He's sent a letter
and wants to write an article regarding the revolution in literature.
So I would like to solicit your opinions.
That's great!
This topic of literary revolution is great.
I really didn't expect
a student who has been overseas for years
to be capable of seeing the purpose of my magazine
so incisively.
Genius!
A kindred spirit!
Alright, Zhong Fu
A sworn friend!
That's enough.
Zhong Fu, a young man's letter
can get you so excited?
Aren't you too ridiculous?
Not by half!
Ideological guidance cannot be idle chit-chat,
but start from a concrete basis
that focuses on the lives of the masses.
"Literary Revolution: A Tentative Proposal"
If this article is written properly,
it will be a bombshell!
Bai Sha, the younger generation will in time surpass us!
This Hu Shi
is too important for our "Youth Magazine."
Must grab him!
Oh Zhong Fu,
in this time and age,
it's not easy to find a genius
who can catch your eye.
Though don't get too hung up on it.
This guy is a doctoral student in the United States,
and a disciple of Professor Dewey.
As if you can grab him just by saying so.
This guy lives in the United States.
Whether he can even come back is an issue.
No, no. This I can guarantee.
He will definitely return to China after completing his studies.
How can one be sure?
This guy, Hu Shi,
is a filial son.
Before he went abroad to study,
his mother arranged a marriage for him.
His mother can't wait to get a grandson.
So she writes him letters every few days
telling him to come back after he finishes his studies to get married.
He would not dare to disobey his mother.
This person is really too wonderful.
His thinking is wonderful.
What?
Grab him!
Grab him as soon as he comes back.
Junman!
Here, let me.
Why is your cough so bad?
You took your medicine?
I did. It's not effective.
It's not effective?
You have to keep taking it.
How can the medicine work if you don't keep taking it?
I've finished it.
But there were no results.
You've finished it.
Ok, alright.
Don't work any more.
Go rest in the house.
Let me sit here for a bit.
Get some air.
Then wait. I will go buy medicine.
You don't need to go.
The drawer has long run out of money.
The money you gave me last month is all used up.
It's an old problem.
It'll pass.
Don't worry. I'm not dying.
Gao Junman!
Don't work anymore!
No one's dying if the firewood's not chopped.
Go inside and rest.
Wait for me.
No one's dying if the firewood's not chopped.
Can't cook if the firewood's not chopped!
Zhong Fu,
why are you here in such a heavy rain?
Just dropping by.
Pour your own tea if you want.
Those the accounts?
So today,
I ran around to collect the money.
To date, our "Youth Magazine"
has sold 2000 copies in total,
breaking even.
The principal has basically been recouped.
That's great.
That's a good thing, right?
Mengzou,
My uh...
This issue's payment for uh,
for my editorial.
Is that included in the capital?
I'm calculating the big accounts.
Haven't had a chance yet to take you into consideration.
Hold on, you have to take me into consideration as well.
If your capital has been recouped
then shouldn't the payment for my editorial
be given back to me?
Alright, then let me take you into consideration right now.
Let me see,
Your manuscript fee, editorial fee
added together
is 138 silver dollars.
However, you've asked three times for an advance.
The first time, for 4 silver dollars.
The second time, also for 4 silver dollars.
The third time, for 10 silver dollars.
18 all together.
138 minus 18
So you should get
120 silver dollars, correct?
I'll give it to you right now.
Fifty.
One hundred.
One twenty.
Take it.