[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Nine]
The most opinionated person in the liberal arts is Gu Hongming.
Many students all raised this issue up.
This Gu Hongming defected to Zhang Xun and participated in the restoration.
He should be removed from Peking University.
If he doesn't attend the meeting today, it's because he's lacking confidence.
Right!
How can you speak like that? Huh?
Regarding Gu Hongming's issue,
we don't need to discuss this here today.
According to the Ministry of Education's request,
the school's appraisal committee members needs to re-elected.
The Ministry of Education in the middle of drafting
the qualifications and conditions of committee members.
About the issue of dismissing a fixed post,
this issue will be handed over to
the new semester's appraisal committee
to discuss a decision.
Does everyone agree?
Agreed!
Good!
Agreed. Agreed. Agreed.
Agreed.
Hu Shi is back!
Hu Shi!
Master Cai.
You fell asleep?
My goodness. You scared me.
Take a look, my beans all fell.
You have to compensate my beans.
Chen Duxiu, ah, Chen Duxiu.
It's still you
who can in the president's room of Peking University
and talk so brazenly.
Brother Jiemin, don't blame me. I'm just so excited.
Hu Shi has returned!
He will reach Shanghai the day after tomorrow.
I want to apply to go to Shanghai to pick him up.
Let him return to the school earlier to register.
You're going to pick him up?
This, isn't this a little excessive?
Master Cai,
what about your three visits just to hire me?
I'm going to Shanghai to pick up a man of talent,
how is this excessive?
They all say you, Chen Duxiu, this condescending person,
is actually not entirely so.
Okay, okay, okay. In any case, you are the Dean of Liberal Arts.
This is a matter of your duty. I won't interfere.
This is simply my job
but the logistics still depends on you.
Relax, I already thought it over for you.
Really?
You need to bring this to Shanghai.
We appoint Mr. Hu Shi, PhD in Philosophy
of Colombia University, United States,
as a professor of liberal arts in Peking University.
Monthly income is 260 silver dollars.
Hold on to this.
Wow.
But right now
Hu Shi still hasn't gotten a PhD.
This contract will be brought down.
You forgot.
What was the letter of appointment I gave you?
Chen Duxiu, former president of Anhui University,
excelling in morals and in academia,
endures and succeeds in the duty of Peking University's Dean of Liberal Arts.
The employer
sometimes just wants the hire.
He can't find any reason to oppose it.
This all needs flexibility.
It's also a matter that is to be used as a last resort.
Crafty old rabbit. Cunning.
Who are you talking about!
Wait a moment. That
Hu Shizhi,
I only saw some of his expositions and poems.
But this person's moral character
and temperament and so on, these I don't really know.
All of this is what I will hear from you.
When he arrives at Peking University, the wages are very high.
I hope that he will not disgrace his mission,
will not fail to live up to our expectations.
He's the exception within the exception.
I believe in my intuition.
I also believe Hu Shi
will not fail to live up your expectations.
Master Cai.
You were looking for me?
Brother Yucai!
Why didn't you tell me when you arrived?
Deqian said you were looking for me.
I hurriedly made my way over.
I'll give you a little introduction.
This is the Dean of Liberal Arts of Peking University, Mr. Chen Duxiu.
This is Mr. Zhou Shuren.
I have heard of your name for a long time, a well-known reputation.
Brother Yucai, I wanted to pay a visit to you from early on.
Didn't expect to encounter you here.
Nice to meet you, nice to meet you.
No need, no need.
Come, come, let's sit down and talk.
Come, come.
Please sit.
Yucai.
I just wanted to talk about two things with you.
The first one
I want to have you come over to Peking University to teach.
Later Fan Yuanlian told me to ask you
to become a concurrent teacher.
Keep your public office at the Ministry of Education.
I thought this way is also good, neither one is neglected.
As long as you can come to Peking University to teach, then it's fine.
You see, it can work.
Master Cai, just arrange for me to take orders.
How is it?
Yucai comes over to Peking University to become a liberal arts professor.
You, as the Dean of Liberal Arts
must immediately arrange his course well.
Excellent!
Another key figure is added to Peking University.
You should say our New Culture Movement
has added another key figure.
I describe the pen in Yucai's hands
like a surgeon's scalpel.
Incomparably sharp.
Yes. Our "New Youth"
was looking forward to Brother Yucai's writings early on.
I still hope Brother Yucai can draft many more.
Give what drafts?
Come to "New Youth".
Be a fellow editor.
If New Culture doesn't have a vanguard like you,
then that is a very big flaw.
How about it?
Yucai, the words that Mr. Zhongfu said just now
is the real thing.
Every word I say is to wish you can come to Peking University.
How is it? Become a member.
I'll listen to Master Cai.
Good! Brother Yucai.
You can join "New Youth".
Extremely honored.
Excellent.
Today is really a good day.
Shizhi (=Hu Shi), Yucai have all come.
Master Cai, then I will prepare to go to Shanghai now.
You hurry and go.
Yucai, wait for me until I come back from Shanghai
to come to my house.
"New Youth" is at my house.
See you later, see you later!
Safe travels!
Yucai.
Zhongfu is a carefree person.
Free and unconstrained.
Don't take offense.
Come, please sit.
The second matter I want to ask you to do
is to design a university crest for Peking University.
University crest?
Okay.
Then do you have any specific opinions and requirements.
I don't have specific requirements.
Yucai, your opinions
is my, Cai Yuanpei's opinion.
Master Cai, you have spoken highly of me.
No, I have never flattered people.
I think the most acute and profound problems
are seen in China at present.
You, Zhou Shuren are one who has seen them.
I believe the crest you will design for Peking University,
the students of Peking University
will continue to wear it for generations to come.
It will never fade.
Okay. I'll try.
Younger brother! Let me have a bite!
Not giving it to you!
Let me have a bite!
Zimei, don't fight over that with Henian
Mom's frying over here.
Mom! Fry one for me.
Aren't I frying here?
It'll be done right away. Don't be anxious.
Henian! Give me a bite!
Junman!
You've come back!
Help me pack my luggage. I am going to Shanghai.
Going to Shanghai?
Right.
When are you going?
Early tomorrow morning.
Then I'll hurry over to walk around Qianmen Street.
What are you going to Qianmen Street for?
To buy Qiaonian and Yannian some things.
I am going there to receive Hu Shi, Hu Shizhi.
Then, you're not going to see the two boys at Shanghai?
Then when I bump into them, I'll meet them.
So, bumping into them means should still buy some things.
Come, come here and fry something for the two.
I'll hurry up and go.
Don't buy too much, okay?
I only have one suitcase, not bringing much.
Alright, just one luggage.
[Shanghai]
Zhongfu, why did take so many bags?
Big bags, small bundles, are you escaping from a famine?
Gao Junman!
I already said I'm only bringing one bag.
All of a sudden, she managed to pack five!
Just for the two punks
to have food, clothes, drinks and tools!
She's almost moved the whole Qianmen pavilion over.
Junman is also very good to the children.
This... this suitcase.
There's still give more bags.
It seems there's eight bags.
Anyways, there's already this many, and I'm not lacking those few.
I'll add another three bags.
Where's Hu Shi?
He went back home.
He went back home?
It's like this. His mother has gotten ill all of a sudden.
Yesterday morning a telegram arrived
in the afternoon he hurried back.
He had me tell you
wait for him to finish handling his family maters, then he'll go to Beijing to hold the teaching position.
As a matter of fact, yesterday
I still wanted to give you a telegram.
You were already on the road, though.
Where are Qiaonian, Yannian?
At Aurora University.
Then I'm going to Jixi, to look for Shizhi.
What are you going to Jixi for?
Someone went back home to handle private matters.
If you go, won't you give people an inconvenience?
How about this. You help me take these bags
to go to Aurora University
and give these things over to Yannian and Qiaonian.
Otherwise these things will go bad.
D-d-don't go.
You also don't need to go to the school.
I'll talk to the two
and get them to come see you.
Then what did I come here for?
Don't be so anxious, listen to me.
There's two friends, they heard you came to Shanghai.
Wants to urgently come see you.
Who?
Yi Baisha, Zou Yongcheng.
They're in Shanghai?
They are in Shanghai.
Brother Zhongfu!
Yongcheng!
Zhongfu.
I missed you, Zhongfu.
Is everything alright you guys?
Hurry and sit.
Here.
You guys... how did you guys get together?
Zhongfu.
My unit got dissolved.
[Zou Yongcheng, styled Qizhi]
Right now I'm in the provincial military governor's office, working as an advisor.
Honestly, there's really nothing to do.
As a matter of fact, Baisha was at Hunan teaching.
Us two often group up to drink our sorrows away.
[Yi Baisha, styled Yuecun, Scholar of the New Culture Movement]
Coming back this time, is to procure arms for the Hunan army.
He is my advisor.
Baisha, you, this master,
why are you also playing with firearms?
Why can't I be playing with firearms?
You also once followed Mr. Cai Yuanpei.
Didn't you make a bomb?
Baisha.
Is there a matter you are not happy with?
He went to Guangzhou and saw Mr. [Sun] Yat-sen who returned.
What did Mr. [Sun] Yat-sen say to you?
Warlords.
Defeat the warlords.
Defeat the warlords. Easier said than done.
How many warlords are there in China?
Which warlord
does not have a foreign power behind him?
Fortunately, Europe at war.
Otherwise,
they would've divided China up early on.
Lamentable, so lamentable.
Such a big country like this
unexpectedly we don't have a unifying leader.
These warlords, each and every one,
has an ugly appearance of "as soon as you finish singing, I go on stage".
Creating a foul atmosphere and causing everything to be in disarray.
Leaving people bitterly disappointed.
In the eyes of these warlords
Mr. [Sun] Yat-sen is actually just a figurehead.
The founder of the Republic.
The leader of the revolutionaries.
Recognized around the world.
The Chinese people's key figure
right now in each and every warlord
is being played with in the palm of their hands.
Suffering time and time again.
This country is finished.