Zhong Fu What time is it already, you're still not going to sleep?
What is there worth seeing outside?
The boat passed Shandong
I feel apprehensive as I near home
There's anger in my heart I want to scold someone
I want to scold Yuan Shikai
I also want to scold this Yuan datou
I don't know what he's thinking
he dared to give Qingdao to Japan
You say, did this guy take the wrong medicine?
Yuan Shikai did not take the wrong medicine
it's our country
that is already incurable
Why do you say that?
Think about it
from guangnian, when Lin Zexu forbid opium
it's been a whole 75 years already
in the middle of this, how many people
thought of different ways
but still couldn't save the Great Qing Dynasty
Sun Zhongshan introduced the republic from the west
people of the country all thought that this...
...was a remedy to save the country and enrich the people
who would have thought, the republic works in other countries
...but inside of China it does not work anymore
three to four years of the republic later
the country is not as good as it used to be
since there is no cure...
...then isn't taking the old way better
these aren't just the thoughts of one or two people,
Bai Sha
Isn't it?
Right now Liang Shiyi and his group
are establishing connections everywhere jumping up and down (?)
joining Yang Hu Gong Yan Ji Dao
...and helping a villain blindly create disturbances
Unreasonable
Yang Du Yan Fu
(idiom) they are the wisest who can have a momentary lapse in judgement
whereas that Liang Shiyi group
are political hooligans with no moral bottom line
I made up a name for them
called "courtesy"
Li Yi Lian, what does it mean?
Courtesy: shameless
Extremely shameless Especially shameless
Good! What a good courtesy!
Zhong Fu, your thinking is clearly unusual
Bai Shao I'm ashamed
it's been more than ten years
Chen Duxiu first learned Kang Liang
followed by Zhong Shan
committed to the political revolution
running this way and that way escaping death many times
guang Japan went 5 times
the results until now...
they still haven't gone anywhere right?
China's matters
by relying on political revolution
doesn't solve the fundamental problem
To get to the bottom of this, we must change our way of thinking
Do you have any new ideas?
I don't dare to say my new ideas
On my return this time
I've made up my mind
For 20 years, I'm not going to touch politics
If you're not going to touch politics, then what do you want to do?
Transform myself. Replace the person, replace the brain
It's not early anymore
Hurry up and go to sleep