[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Two]
Brothers have to go to work now.
I can't play with you this time.
Next time?
Let's go.
Goodbye Aunt.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Come.
Take all the buns.
Brother, you promised to give me a grasshopper!
I'll keep my promise!
Come home if you need to.
Thank you Aunt.
[Songshan Road, French Concession, Shanghai]
Pear paste pastries... sweet and savoury,
a mouthful of delight!
The song goes:
[Chen Henian, youngest son of Chen Duxiu]
Xiao Fangqing in the Pearl Tower
is so happy to meet
Xiao Qingqing in "The Legend of the White Snake".
Xiao Fangqing
is so happy
to the movies with her.
Hey! Selling pear pastries!
Good, stop!
Mr Menzou is here!
[Wang Mengzou, Manager of Yadong Library]
Menzou!
Junman!
I've brought you Zhong Fu back from the dock!
Where?
At the back!
Look!
Zimei! Henian! Look who's back!
It's Dad! Call Dad!
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhong Fu, famous revolutionary]
Why don't you have an umbrella?
Zimei! Henian!
Qiaonian? Yannian? Where are they?
Let's go home first.
Okay, go, go, go.
Let's go home!
Thank you, Menzou.
Go, go, go!
What are you doing?
What are you doing out in the rain?
Tasting the Jiangnan rain.
Quick, quick, quick!
Were you that stupid in Japan?
Look at the rain on you!
There's raindrops all over!
What's a drop of rain?
When I was in Japan,
I was covered in lice.
Once.
Then Zhang Shizhao asked me to edit an issue.
I locked myself in my room,
I didn't leave the house for half a month.
Then the article was finished.
I went out,
Yi Baisha looked at me and said:
What are those spots on your body?
I looked down and it was all...
Don't say, don't say, don't say.
Mr Chen.
You've suffered.
Come. Sit.
Sit with me and listen to the rain for a while.
There is no revolution without suffering,
but I brought this misery upon myself.
I like to... I like to enjoy it.
It's just that... I got you into trouble.
You're a talented student from Beijing Normal University,
suffering with me.
I'm sorry.
As long as the family can be together,
whatever the suffering and hardship,
I'm not afraid.
It's just that Yannian and Qiaonian don't want to go home.
I don't feel well.
Zhong Fu.
Why don't you go and get the two children tomorrow
and bring them home?
Don't let them roam around outside.
I'm not going to pick them up.
These two boys have a lot of backbone.
It's good to go out and make your own living.
Yannian and Qiaonian
are two good boys with big ambitions.
After the May 9th National Disgrace,
they both came to Shanghai to study.
Seeing our family's difficulties,
they had brought from the countryside
100 silver yuan for tuition
and gave it to me.
They went out to work on their own.
I tried to give it back to them
but they wouldn't listen.
You said Shanghai docks are so rough.
What would happen if something happened to them?
Zhong Fu.
I'm begging you.
You go and bring them both home.
Junman.
When I was abroad,
I heard a song from Europe
called "The Internationale".
Although the lyrics have not been translated into Chinese,
there are a few lines in it
I was very impressed by.
The idea is
there is no saviour
or there is no fairy god.
To create happiness for all
is up to us.
Well sung... well said.
From large countries to small individuals,
one should forge their own destiny.
Trusting your life
to your father and family.
You can't rely on that.
So, what is the job of the father?
Where has your duty as a father gone?
It is my duty
to let them know
how to be live up to
the social and historical responsibilities of this country.
In these troubled times,
to be a son of I, Chen Duxiu,
one must first work hard on one's heart and soul.
Starve the body and the skin, but not the soul.
Act in accordance with the law,
so your heart is willing
to endure what it once could not.
You are a thinker against the ways of Confucius and Mencius.
Why did you make a statement
out of Mencius' quotes?
Yuan Shikai wants to make Confucianism the state religion,
of course I want to oppose it.
But make no mistake,
I am against
the three principles of Confucianism that are poisoning the people.
Neither Confucius nor Mencius.
All right, all right, I can't talk you out of it.
Step inside.
It's cold.
Let's go.
[Yadong Library]
Brother.
That thing, put it in the jar.
Is it fine?
It's fine.
You're all set, right?
There is no point in playing chess. Put it back.
Ready to go Huangshan, Maofeng?
Zhong Fu!
Brother Zhong Fu!
Put it here.
Come on, come on, we're waiting for you.
Zhong Fu, ladies and gentlemen!
Everyone's here!
Brother Zhong Fu, we're all waiting for you!
Zishou.
Zipei.
[Yi Baisha, styled Yue Cun, scholar of the New Culture movement]
Zhong Fu.
Baisha.
Yongcheng.
[Zou Yongcheng, styled Qi Zhi]
Since we left the boat, I've missed you.
Greetings, gentlemen.
Come on, you're barging in.
Go and meet us at the front!
No, I'm not going to meet him.
Why is this child so stubborn?
You tell me, he's still your old man,
then the bones are still attached to the tendons.
Where did all the hate come from?
I don't have a grudge against him,
but I just don't go to see him.
Same temper as your father.
I'm sure of it.
I can't get it back with nine oxen.
The fire is good.
Why are you, Wang Menzou,
so stingy?
I'm invited to dinner,
not at a restaurant, but at a home.
How much money do you save?
He said it! I do save money.
What would you like to eat?
I prepared it all yesterday.
The cook was also taken from Zishou's house.
I didn't spend any mony on this.
I can attest.
What Menzou said is true in every sense of the word.
[Chen Zishou, owner of Qunyi Book Club]
Our family cook
was dragged here by him.
Zhong Fu, I'm borrowing the cook's skills.
You should also write us a couple of words.
To each his own.
He gave me a reception
by borrowing the cook from you.
He should be grateful to you.
What's it to do with me?
Me!
Zhong Fu, who is the stingy one?
Of course, he's stingy one!
And the famous Yadong Library
has always been housed in this alley.
I've tried so many times to get him to move out
but he won't listen!
It's easy to move out!
Wang Mengzou, I tell you,
we are doing great things with a bang.
If you want to die,
just cower in the alleyway.
If you want to live,
you have to move out of the alleyway
and onto the main road.
All right, all right.
You're standing around talking,
then sit down and talk.
Everyone sit down.
Sit down, sit down.
[Chen Qiaonian, second son of Chen Duxiu]
Qiaonian.
You're too young to hold a grudge.
This is a lotus leaf and yellow beef feet dish.
Serve it to your father.
Meet him.
Give him a surprise.
OK, I'll send him up later
and surprise him.
[Chen Yannian, eldest son of Chen Duxiu]
That's right!
Today, everyone invited to
firstly
celebrate Zhong Fu's return to the country.
That's the second.
Since the failure of the Second Revolution,
We revolutionaries
have been scattered to the winds.
We went our separate ways and hid into hiding.
Some died, some were wounded.
Today, having us all here together
after the disaster
is not easy.
The situation now
is that European powers are at war.
Originally it was our country's
time to take a break.
But what about the Japanese?
They took advantage of the situation,
by proposing
the Twenty-One Demands of powers in Shandong.