[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode One]
In 1915,
World War I
entered its second year of unprecedented tragedy.
While Germany was distracted in the European theater,
Japan stepped up its expansion in China.
During this time period,
since the Second Revolution's failure,
(Second Revolution: 1913 revolt by the governors of several southern Chinese provinces as well as supporters of Sun Yat-sen and the Kuomintang against the Beiyang government of the Republic of China led by Yuan Shikai.)
Sun Yat-sen and others were forced into exile overseas.
Bourgeois revolutionaries
were unable to carry out the anti-imperialist and anti-feudal struggle to the end.
Domestic political chaos,
the unbearable suffering of the people,
internal trouble and external aggression
had once again thrown China into turmoil.
Mr. President,
Japanese diplomat Hioki Eki has sent an ultimatum
to be answered within forty-eight hours.
What does the ultimatum say?
[Yuan Shikai, President of the Republic of China]
If the Twenty-One Demands
[Liang Shiyi, styled Yifu, Secretary General of the Presidential Office of the Republic of China]
are not accepted within the time frame,
then Japan will take necessary measures.
[Cao Rulin, styled Runtian, Vice Minister of Foreign Affairs of the Republic of China]
What does he want?
Hioki Eki said
Japan is to take over Shandong as they took over the northeast.
The Japanese... They still want us dead.
This afternoon, the Ministry of War reported
that Japanese naval formations
are heading for our southeast coast.
What?
Does he still want another Jiawu War (=First Sino-Japanese War)?
Make no mistake.
I am Yuan Shikai,
not Li Hongzhang.
(Li Hongzhang: politician, general and diplomat of the late Qing dynasty, who directed Chinese forced during the First Sino-Japanese War)
For a long time, there have been discussions in Japan
advocating for Japanese intervention
in our country's Yangtze River basin as soon as possible.
Useless... Useless...
Didn't you tell Hioki Eki that
it's not that I, Yuan Shikai, who disagreed with the Twenty-One Demands?
It's the people who are rebelling so much.
When they (the Japanese) hid Sun Yat-sen and Huang Xing in Japan,
didn't they say we should respect public opinion?
Mr. President, our appeal has worked.
The Japanese agree that the articles in Section 5 (which will give Japan decisive voice in China's financing, policing and governmental affairs)
can be discussed later.
But... the treaty must be signed immediately.
What's the response of Ministry of Foreign Affairs?
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs obeys the orders of the President.
How cunning!
Then just accept the terms of the Japanese.
Now Sun Yat-sen, Huang Xing and the others will make trouble again.
All these people have gone overseas.
It won't be a big deal.
Right.
Runtian, tell the Japanese
the treaty will be signed,
but the articles in Section 5 cannot be accepted.
This is the bottom line.
I gave him face,
he should also give me some.
Understood, Mr. President.
Which day is the deadline proposed by the Japanese?
The ninth.
Then wait until the evening of the ninth
to inform the Japanese.
Extra! Extra!
Today's extra is very strange!
President Yuan Shikai
is selling out the country!
The wastrel, sells, sells, sells!
His backbone simply has no strength.
But the common masses won't say yes,
they were seized with fury and wrath.
Look at this woman! So angry, she stomps on the extra!
Look at this man! So angry, he breaks his crutch!
On 9 May, 1915,
Yuan Shikai ordered the
signing with Japan a treaty of national betrayal and humiliation --
the Twenty-One Demands.
According to this treaty,
China will recognize Japan's inheritance of
all German rights and interests in Shandong.
Japan will enjoy special privileges
in southern Manchuria and eastern Inner Mongolia.
Japan will acquire, in China,
various railway construction rights, and so on.
The Beiyang government's treasonous acts
were strongly opposed by the nation.
All major cities in China,
such as Beijing, Guangzhou, Wuhan,
Qingdao, and etc.,
had held large-scale demonstrations.
Shanghai dockers went on strike
announcing a boycott of Japanese goods.
Workers in Hankow, Zhenjiang, Hanyang, Changsha,
Fuzhou and other places
held various protests one after another,
refusing to recognize the Twenty-One Demands
and vowing to avenge national humiliation,
which demonstrated a firm anti-imperialist stance
and a strong patriotic passion.
Exiles like Sun Yat-sen, Huang Xing and their followers
call for revolutionaries to return to China to oppose Yuan.
[Waseda University, Japan]
Come and see this!
Latest news from home!
Shameless! Insane!
[Li Dazhao, styled Shouchang, Waseda University Student]
We have been fighting for so long,
only to gain this type of result.
[Gao Yihan, Meiji University Student]
Do we really have no way out?
This kind of big event
is not something you and I can control.
Let's take it easy, and eat first.
Faced with such national crisis, nobody is in the mood to eat.
We all vowed to share weal and woe with our country,
how... how can you still eat?
You can't do anything without eating!
Students! Countrymen!
Heaven kills, the war clouds fly.
The Wa nation (=Japanese) seize their chance, and pressing upon our Xiayu (=Chinese territory).
Students in Japan, detained in an exotic land,
looking back at Shenzhou (=China), and looking up to heaven, sorrowful and enraged!
Now that our country has fallen and our people have died,
there is no need to hold back from taking actions against the evildoer for fear of involving good people.
We should have the determination to press ahead.
The arch-usurper Yuan Shikai
wants to restore the imperial system and become the emperor.
The Republic of China is in imminent peril!
The traitor Yuan Shikai
has signed the Twenty-One Demands.
The Chinese nation is in imminent peril!
Countrymen, the Republic is perishing,
Qingdao is about to be lost.
Countrymen, what do you say?
Return home! Return home!
Overthrow Yuan! Return to China!
Return home!
Overthrow Yuan!
Okay, stop yelling.
How do you guys have the power to overthrow Yuan?
Just don't make trouble for the country.
What did you say?
Zhang Fengzai,
now that our country is in crisis and the Republic is perishing,
yet you guys are behaving rather peculiar here.
Can you still regard yourselves as Chinese?
Do you have any patriotism left in you?
That's right! Are you Chinese?!
China has been in this state
for much more than a day or two.
Can you save the country like this?
It's all because of you apathetic people,
China has now fallen into such an abyss.
Yeah! It is because of you!
Because of us?
We won't go along with this accusation.
If it weren't for those stupid revolutionaries.
Had they not tried to copy the American republican system,
China would have been a constitutional monarchy.
It wouldn't have turned out to be
the grotesque situation we find ourselves in today.
Yuan Shikai's attempt to introduce a constitutional monarchy
was essentially a return to the correct path.
This is the way to save China,
and the foundation of prosperity.
Nonsense!
Ridiculous! Ridiculous!
The idea of a democratic republic
is already well established.
Aren't you driving backwards in history?
Yeah! That's right! Driving backwards!
We are the ones driving backwards in history?
Or is it you revolutionaries,
who ignored China's national conditions?
Students! Countrymen!
Kang Youwei has long said
a revolution is not a good thing for a country.
The French Revolution,
eighty years of turmoil and bloodshed of millions.
Furthermore, the Chinese people are not yet enlightened.
In this case,
the forced imposition of a republican system
will be like duckweed floating on water, with no roots!
Zhang Fengzai, what you just said
is absolutely absurd!
Kang Youwei's words
have been refuted by many revolutionary martyrs.
The revolution will certainly shed blood.
But I would like to ask you,
will the constitutional monarchy not shed any blood?
Right!
[Zhang Shizhao, styled Xingyan, famous social activist forced into exile in Japan for his participation in the "Second Revolution" against Yuan Shikai]
Yeah! Good point!
Britain, Austria, Germany, Italy,
which one of these countries has not experienced
many changes
and made great sacrifices,
before it has achieved real social progress?
Another thing I want to ask you is,
what did you mean when you just said
our people are not yet enlightened?
That's demonstrably false!
Since the Xinhai Revolution,
the entire population's thinking
has already undergone earth-shaking changes.
The unanimous rejection of Yuan at home and abroad
is the solid evidence of that!
The more the nation is in peril,
the more it should awaken people's consciousness
and invigorate the national spirit.
And if the idea of republicanism
is to be instilled in the people,
it is necessary to overthrow the feudal ideology.
Zhang Fengzai, those who go against the tide of history
will be drowned by the torrent of the times.
For the love of country,
we must save our country and overthrow Yuan.
For our Chinese nation,
we must save our country and overthrow Yuan!
Save the country! Overthrow Yuan!
Well said!
Mr. Xingyan. Mr. Xingyan.
Hello students.
Shouchang's words
not only were on just grounds, but also came from the bottom of his heart,
impassioned, engaging and on point.
Excellent!
Zhongfu, what do you think?
Zhongfu? Chen Duxiu?
This is Chen Duxiu?
Chen Duxiu!
Is this Chen Duxiu?
Why does he look like that?
[Chen Duxiu, styled Zhongfu, famous revolutionary forced into exile in Japan for his participation in the "Second Revolution" against Yuan Shikai]
Could it be Chen Duxiu?
It can't be.
As you said,
he is a very intelligent young man.
Chen Duxiu.
Why are you eating here?
I was just passing by
seeing them bickering.
No one was eating.
Food should not be wasted at any time.
It's shameful to waste food.
What time is it? You're still eating here?
Are you Chen Duxiu?
I am, yes.
He really is!
I am Chen Duxiu.
He is! He's Chen Duxiu!
Quiet, everyone!
Quiet!
Since Mr. Zhongfu is here,
we would like to ask you,
what should be done to save China in your opinion?
I think that
such a country is beyond saving.
What did you say?
Are you a Chinese? How dare you say that?
Chen Duxiu. Are you talking in human language?
Simply shameless!
Shameless!
What are you doing?
You've gone too far!
Mr. Zhongfu, is what you just said
really what you think?
Yes, of course.
But, what I meant to say...
You see?!
Students! You have seen it!
This is your so called revolutionary!
A great revolutionary!
Do you know what he once said?
He said he didn't care for his country's subjugation!
What else?
What's terrible of being a slave to a subjugated country?
What's lovable about a country of brutalized people?
This is the real traitor! A hanjian!
Traitor! Hanjian!
Hanjian!
Get out of the way!
Don't strike
Let's just talk!
Don't do it!
Stop!
Don't strike
Don't do it!
Mr. Zhongfu, go!
Let's just talk! Don't strike!
Come on, this way!
Don't do it, people, calm down!
Listen to me for a moment!
Mr. Xingyan has a message for everyone!
Come on, everyone, allow me to say something here.
Come on, come on!
Alright.
Alright, alright, no one is following.
Take a break, take a breather.
I'm nothing like Chen Duxiu, right?
Just a little different from
my imagination.
So what do you imagine I should be?
Are you okay?
I apologize for the situation.
It's okay, I've seen a lot of these.
Your article
"Self Consciousness on Patriotism", I've read it.
But I have many doubts and questions.
I would like to seek you explanation, is that okay?
I know that you, Li Dazhao, are from Hebei.
Yanzhao (=Hebei in Warring States period) is known for its fervent and sorrowful people, they insist relentlessly.
But China nowadays
is in need of real heroes who insist relentlessly.
Please ask your questions.
You said that patriotism should have a position,
and that we should not, under the pretext of patriotism,
be one of Yuan Shikai's obedient subjects.
Then according to you,
as long as Yuan Shikai is in power,
people should not be patriotic.
You stubborn man, you misunderstood.
I meant to say,
patriotism should have a position,
and patriotism should not be confused
with loyalty to Yuan Shikai,
or covering up Yuan Shikai's usurp of state power,
under the pretext of patriotism.
This is similar to what the statements you made earlier,
is it not?
That Yuan Shikai
keeps saying that he represents the country.
He is deliberately confusing different concepts.
If patriotism has no position,
then we simply have no reason
to overthrow Yuan Shikai.
I completely agree.
I think the top priority today is
to inspire the people to be truly patriotic.
Right now, China is being divided up by the Western powers.
If everyone is not patriotic,
then the country will definitely perish.
Shouchang, let me I ask you,
what are the Western powers relying on to carve up China?
Their powerful navies and strong weaponry.
No!
You are talking about the Opium War and naval failure of the Jiawu War.
Now the foreign powers are dividing China by giving loans.
The Chinese government
borrows foreign debt from Western countries every year,
accounting for more than half of the treasury's revenue.
In a country without productivity,
it relies exclusively on putting up its national tax and railways as collaterals,
and taking loans to maintain its political power.
What do you expect from a country like this?
That's exactly why we're going to overthrow Yuan,
overthrow this corrupt government,
and build a new nation.
No!
Can China be saved by political revolution?
China's problems are ingrained habits that are hard to break.
Can we solve the problems simply by changing the leaders or governments?
So according to you,
our China has no way out?
There is a way, but the way out is not the old way.
Only when we find a new way out,
China will not perish.
What is the old way?
The succession of political regimes,
the replacing of an old dynasty
with a new dynasty.
The cycle repeats itself. This is the old way.
And what is the new way?
I don't know yet.
That's what I'm looking for.
Shouchang, I appreciate your insights and your talent.
Will you look for this new path with me?
To find a way to save China
is my life's work.
I will.
Good.
Zhongfu!
You've both come here
and made us look for you!
Tickets... we have the tickets.
Tomorrow we can go back home.
Excellent. Finally we can go back.
Zhongfu, before you head back,
you finally got to see Shouchang.
It's not in vain that you took
the crime of being a traitor.
Not in vain... not in vain...
See me?
Yeah.
He's here to see you today.
Ever since he read from the "The Tiger",
your article,
he's been wanting to see you.
Was it worth the trip?
The harvest is rich, like a heaven-sent gift!
You... you always stay indoors to write articles
not allowing us to care for you,
or ask questions,
making yourself like a beggar.
With you unkempt hair, dirty face, and body-full of lice,
[Yi Baisha, styled Yuecun, famous thinker forced into exile in Japan for participating in the "Second Revolution" against Yuan Shikai]
You'll definitely scare Junman when you get back home!
Hurry back!
Cut your hair, take a bath, and change your clothes.
I can take a bath,
but I only have one set of clothes. There's nothing else to change into.
Alright.
Brother Zhongfu. Wait.
It's going to be windy at sea. Take care of yourself.
Okay, then I'll accept your gift.
Shouchang, I owe you three favors today.
In the future, you must remember to ask my return of favors.
What are they?
One is to help me get out of trouble.
Second is to lend me clothes.
And the third?
I scrounged your meal.
But before I had enough to eat,
I got chased away.
Then keep scrounging!
Can I buy you all a meal?
None of us has eaten yet.
Then we'll all scrounge along.
Good, Brother Zhongfu, this way.
Zhongfu, what time is it already, you're still not going to bed?
What is worth seeing outside?
The ship just passed Shandong.
I feel apprehensive as I come near home.
There's anger in my heart. I want to scold someone.
I want to scold Yuan Shikai.
I also want to scold this Big Head Yuan (homophone for "squanderer").
I don't know what he's thinking,
he had the guts give away Qingdao to Japan.
What would you say, did this guy take the wrong medicine (meaning, lose his mind)?
Yuan Shikai did not take the wrong medicine.
It's our country
that is already incurable.
Why do you say that?
Think about it.
Since Lin Zexu banned opium in the Daoguang era,
it's been seventy-five years.
Throughout this entire time, how many people
thought of different ways
but still couldn't save the Great Qing dynasty.
Sun Yat-sen introduced the Republic from the West,
our compatriots all thought that this
was a remedy to save the country and enrich the people.
Who would have thought, the republic works in other countries,
but inside of China, it does not work anymore.
After three or four years of the Republic,
the country is somehow even worse than it used to be.
Since there is no cure,
then isn't it easier to take the old way.
This type of sentiments is not shared just by one or two people.
Baisha.
Isn't it the case?
You know what, that Liang Shiyi's gang is now
jumping up and down in tandem everywhere.
Even Yang Hugong (Yang Du, politician), Yan Jidao (Yan Fu, military officer, newspaper editor, translator and writer, known for introducing western ideas to China)
also serving their tiger master to make a scene.
Preposterous.
Yang Du, Yan Fu.
They are the wisest who can have a momentary lapse in judgment.
Whereas that Liang Shiyi group
are political hooligans with no moral bottom line.
I made up a name for them
called Li Yilian.
(lit. propriety, righteousness, honesty)
Li Yilian, what does this mean?
Li Yilian -- lacking shame!
(lit. propriety, righteousness, honesty, and a sense of shame; upheld as the "four social bonds" in ancient China)
Extremely shameless! Most shameless of all!
Brilliant! What a good Li Yilian!
Zhongfu, your thinking is clearly extraordinary!
Baisha, I'm ashamed.
For more than ten years,
I, Chen Duxiu, first learned after Kang Liang (Kang Youwei & Liang Qichao),
followed by [Sun] Yat-sen,
committed to the political revolution,
rushing about, escaping death many times.
I have escaped to Japan alone for five times.
As a result, however,
nothing is achieved still, right?
In terms of the future of China,
political revolution alone
won't solve the fundamental problem.
To get to the bottom of this, we must change our way of thinking.
Do you have any new ideas?
I wouldn't dare to call them new ideas.
but on my return this time,
I've made up my mind.
For twenty years, I'm not going to touch upon politics.
If you're not going to touch upon politics, then what do you want to do?
Be reborn. Change the body, change the mind.
It's late now.
Hurry up and go to sleep.
Zhongfu, what time is it already?
What are you still sitting there for?
It's so dark out there,
you can't see anything at all.
Go to bed now. Turn off the lights, okay?
I do see.
Students of our generation,
[Waseda University dormitory]
especially among the people, should bear great responsibilities.
Those who research the spiritual realms (i.e., liberal arts and social science)
should produce beautiful literature
and noble thinking
to contribute to the spiritual development of our nation.
Those who research material realms (i.e., natural science)
should frequently express their profound thinking
and apply them exquisitely in real life
to seek the development of our country's military technology and instruments.
The power of spirit is omnipotent,
and if held with sincerity and perseverance,
one will lead a magnificent and meaningful endeavor.
Based on even the fainted glow of conscience,
Cao Mo will avenge shame
(cf. legend of Lu General Cao Mo forcing Duke Huan of Qi to return Lu's territory after three defeats)
and Goujian will take revenge,
(cf. King Goujian of Yue's conquering of Wu, after Goujian was captured and enslaved by the Wu king)
Times like those will eventually come.
Brother Fengzai, I say, you are really capable.
You have everything prepared here!
This mah-jong game, I love it the most!
I also love playing mah-jong!
Brother Fengzai, you are truly wise and brilliant.
You managed to get everyone tickets for a second class cabin.
If we were in the fourth class cabin,
next to the pauper,
It would have been so boring!
Right! So boring!
All of these are not worth mentioning.
My second uncle said
When Yuan Shikai becomes the emperor,
he will be the head of imperial palace affairs.
When you return home, help us with more publicity.
When the time comes, I will give you your due.
No problem!
West wind (mah-jong tile name).
I say, Brother Fengzai,
for the sake of Yuan Shikai,
we've already given up our opportunities go study abroad.
You have to tell your second uncle about it, right?
Let me guess,
you're all having the same doubts?
Of course!
Okay!
Then let me help you all clear these doubts.
My second uncle says,
as long as the work is done,
we can all go study at Peking University.
Are you serious?
Then we will have boundless prospects.
This is great! Peking University!
I was just waiting for this promise from you!
Zhongfu!
Somebody made way for you,
why didn't you acknowledge them?
This is unreasonable.
Who is this person?
He is a famous Chinese United League (Tongmenghui) veteran,
General Zou Yongcheng, commander of the Third Army of Hunan-Henan Coalition Forces.
You need to give him an apology.
I've always been uninterested in bureaucrats.
Look at you!
Greetings Mr. Yi Baisha.
[Zou Yongcheng, styled Qizhi, Chinese United League member]
Greetings General Zou.
Mr. Zhongfu.
General Zou isn't just any official.
In the second year or the Republic, when Song Jiaoren (political leader and a founder of KMT) was assassinated,
General Zou deeply felt that the Republic would fall apart.
He left a suicide poem,
jumped into the Huangpu River in anger to commit suicide.
"After more than ten years of vigorous revolution,
Hu Lu (initially referring to Xiongnu, later extended to general northern invading nomads such as the ruling Manchus of Qing) was expelled with their ancestral whip.
Only to find that the ape (homophone of Yuan) somersaulted out,
the Republic becomes a dream and I shall return to Heaven."
How noble and majestic!
Not really, I'm ashamed of the being an incompetent.
Jumping into Huangpu River to commit suicide.
Just an attempt?
Indeed, it was an attempt.
Luckily I was rescued by fishermen.
If so,
I actually think you are a fool.
How can a revolutionary kill himself so easily?
I, Chen Duxiu, in this life,
would never do anything stupid to kill myself and alienate myself from the revolution.
Zhongfu!
General Zou, I apologize.
It's alright.
Zhongfu!
You were too overbearing.
Being ruthless does not make you a true hero.
Maybe one day,
I will also be like Qu Yuan (poet and politician during the Warring State period, known for his patriotism),
jumping into a river to commit suicide for my country.
At that time, will you also come ridicule me?
Sorry, Baisha.
I'm not in a good mood, I forgot my manners.
Forgive me.
Junman is coughing up blood.
She is too young to suffer from tuberculosis.
Yannian, Qiaonian, those two unfilial sons
were not at home taking care of their mother
but recently came to Shanghai as well.
Poor woman, she is both an aunt and a stepmother,
She's sick with no money,
and has to take care of a family with five to six people.
I really don't know
how they would survive.
You... This way of managing the family is questionable.
I heard you insist on not covering
living expenses for the two brothers, Yannian and Qiaonian,
and instead, leaving them to work while studying,
providing for themselves.
At such a young age,
who can take this kind of suffering?
Why can't they take this kind of suffering?
If I had money I still wouldn't give it to them.
Not to mention, I don't have any money.
[Shanghai French Concession Handling Station]
Careful, brother!
Come!
[Chen Yannian, eldest son of Chen Duxiu]
[Chen Qiaonian, second son of Chen Duxiu]
Come!
Here!
Gloomy men, let's sing a tune! Heiyo!
Gloomy women, come snivel! Heiyo!
If there's any matter, then sing!
You old thing!
This old thing!
You can't even carry one bag, you still want to carry two?
Spilling beans all over the ground!
You idler!
If you can, then do it. If you can't, get out of here!
I'll beat you to death! I'll let you be an idler
I'll let you be an idler! I'll let you...
How can you hit him?
What are you doing!
Don't move!
Don't move! What are you doing!
What do you want!
How can you just hit people like that?
Are you okay?
How can I?
Because I'm in charge here!
Hey! How come it's you again?
Did you want to take the whipping for him?
Get out of my sight!
His leg already has an injury.
What's the matter if things fell on the ground?
Isn't it fine just to pick them up?
What the fuck does his injury have to do with me!
You have to take responsibility for delaying business!
But you still can't beat someone up!
I just did. So what?
Believe it or not, I'll beat both of you together!
What are you doing?
Don't strike!
You can't beat us!
Want to rebel, is that right?
Want to rebel, is that right!
You are quite a righteous brat, huh?
Fine, today I'll let you handle this first issue.
Old Jia's work is your responsibility now.
None of you should get involved.
Whoever comes forward will also do his work.
Come!
I'll do it.
Me too.
Count me in!
Since you two volunteered first, you two do it.
Come!
No more nonsense!
Who's next? Break it up!
What are you still looking at? Scatter!
Turn it over
There's nothing to look at, all of you go back to work!
Grab here.
Okay.
Here!
Lift
All right, all right. Go do your job.
What are you staring at!
Pick up all these beans for me.
If you miss even one grain, I'll kill you.
Quickly!
Hurry up!
Older brother.
I can't hold on anymore.
Hurry and put it down! Don't injure your waist.
That's not it, my waistband just broke.
Well then...
Put your legs together!
Don't move, alright.
What are you messing around for? Quickly!
Take your legs out.
Put on your shoes.
You don't even want your shoes on now, huh?
Let go! Let go!
Let go of me.
What's going on?
Let go of me!
You guys can't be like this!
Stop right now! What do you guys want to do!
Let go. Let go of me!
Get your hands off of me!
What are you guys doing!
You can't be like this!
Let go of me!
What are you doing
They're hurting someone!
That's a girl!
What are you doing?
Let go! Let go!
Hands off! Take your hands off right now!
What the heck is going on down there?
A live performance of "Romance of the Western Chamber" on board!
Let me go!
Out of the way!
Stop fighting!
Who!
Who did it?
Who threw it?
What are you guys doing?
Do you want to steal money or jump into the sea and escape?
Our boat tickets were stolen!
That's why we came on the deck!
Don't strike!
Just forget it!
Let go!
Stop fighting!
Great!
Stop the ruckus!
You are supposed to be quiet and courteous here.
We are on the ocean.
This boat belongs to Japan.
People who don't have a boat ticket must buy one.
So, everyone, please understand that
we conducted a secret investigation
and found out that those two originally did not have boat tickets.
Therefore
these two must buy boat tickets.
Let these two youths off.
As for the boat tickets, I'll pay for them.
Okay, as long as the tickets are purchased.
It's not okay! You guys...
You have to apologize to the young Chinese couple.
This is our Japanese ocean liner,
we are carrying out official business.
There is no reason to apologize, you guys better not go too far.
Is beating people part of carrying out official business?
Is humiliating a woman part of carrying out official business?
Is taking off a girl's clothes part of carrying out official business?
I'm telling you guys...
you Japanese people are abusing your power,
willfully insulting us Chinese people.
This is an insult to our China!
This is the high seas!
This matter
is big enough to cause an international incident.
Are you trying to
cause enough troubles out of hand?
Apologize!
Apologize! Apologize!
Apologize! Apologize! Apologize! Bad guys, apologize!
Okay! I got it!
You two quickly apologize.
Sorry. Sorry.
Hey, let's go!
We won!
This is the victory? What did you win?
Just three words "I am sorry", and it's over?
That's right!
Does this count as victory?
Keep fighting!
Come back and keep fighting!
What are you saying!
Are you still human?
Seeing your fellow citizen being bullied...
not coming out to lend a hand...
instead, you are on the side making sarcastic remarks.
Are you still Chinese?
Do you still know what shame is?
You know what shame is,
what's the point of showing off here?
If you are so capable, go join the battle in Europe,
go exterminate the Eight-Nation Alliance.
That's right!
That's what is called capability.
You!
What do you want to do?
A Chinese person beating another Chinese?
Come.
Let all the foreigners see clearly...
how Chinese people bully each other.
Come.
Do you see it?
Chinese people are bullying each other!
Come!  Everyone, come and see!
Stop quarreling, all of you go back now!
Go away.
All of you go back.
Back to your cabin.
Don't be angry, don't lower yourself to their level.
Step aside.
Raise your foot a little.
You are stepping on my tile.
What tile?
Little... Little chick it seems like.
You eyesight seems pretty poor.
It's a cake.
Play often?
Why did you throw away the tile!
Fellow countrymen being insulted
is far less important
than your mah-jong game, right?
What the hell does this have to do with playing Mah-jong!
What did you throw away my tile for?
How can they be justified for sneaking on board without tickets?
The reason why our country is not prospering...
is that the people are not enlightened.
Do you have to go that far?!
Playing mah-jong...
has nothing to be with either he prosperity of the nation or the enlightenment of the people!
What did you throw away my tile for?
You guys still want to lose more face?
Us Chinese people arguing amongst ourselves here,
turning into laughing stocks to the foreigners.
Everybody, go back to your own cabin. Right now!
Let's go.
Mr. Zhongfu, are you alright?
I'm alright.
General Yongcheng,
Please accept my formal apology to you for
my lack of manners from earlier.
You are a brave fellow!
That's too much of a compliment.
Thank you sirs!
Sir,
For the money for boat tickets
we will for sure repay you as soon as possible.
No need, no need.
We are all Chinese people
We're supposed to help each other.
Thank you!
Mr. Zhongfu.
You helped us, despite what happened yesterday.
I wholeheartedly am grateful to you.
What about the events of yesterday?
You forgot,
At Waseda,
I spit on you.
How about if I didn't forget?
Should I spit back at you?
You spit on me
out of your courage and uprightness.
Today we helped to defend you
out of our courage and uprightness.
But relying merely on courage and uprightness,
when will this fight ever end?
Do you understand the reasoning behind this?
I am all ears for our instructions.
Good.
Then let's go back to our cabin to chat.
General Yongcheng, please.
Let's go.  Come on.
Qiaonian,
All set. Now I won't be afraid that it's gonna fall.
Here.
Brother Yannian, Brother Qiaonian!
What are you doing here?
What tasty food are you eating?
I also want to eat!
[Chen Zimei, daughter of Chen Duxiu]
Aunt!
Yannian, Qiaonian.
[Gao Junman, wife of Chen Duxiu]
So hard to eat!
What's wrong Zimei?
Don't eat this anymore.
Aunt brought over some buns for you guys.
They just came out of the boiler.
Eat the buns.
Aunt, we won't eat these.
Aunt is not an stranger.
What is it that you can't eat these?
You can take them.
Thank you aunt!
I brought you guys some egg soup too.
Here.
Fresh out of the pot.
Thank you aunt!
Yannian. Come, eat some buns!
Aunt, we did buy these naans.
It's true that they don't look good. But they're actually quite tasty!
Where's Henian?
He's not feeling very well.
I had a neighbor help look after him.
Yannian, Qiaonian,
Aunt has come here many times to convince you guys.
But you are always stubbornly not willing to come home with me.
Now that our father is about to come back,
come home with me.
We won't go back.
We don't have anything to do with that person.
But you guys working outside like this...
is truly onerous!
You can't even get a bite of something warm.
Come home with me please.
You'd after all be able to have some warm food.
Is that okay?
Aunt, please don't try to persuade us anymore.
We will rely on ourselves.
This is our principle.
Zimei,
your brothers are going to go to work.
This time we can't play with you.
Next time, okay?
Let's go!
Goodbye, aunt.
Wait a minute!
Here.
Take all of these buns with you!
Older brother, you promised that you will get me some grasshoppers!
It's a deal! As your brother I will keep my promises for sure!