[The Age of Awakening]
[Episode Eighteen]
The theme of this week's book club
is Russia's October Revolution.
[Zhao Shiyan, styled Qinsheng, Student at The High School Affiliated to Beijing Normal University]
The main topic of our discussion is
whether Russia's October Revolution
can be used for reference by China,
despite the limitations in materials.
Let us please welcome Student Deng Zhongxia
to give us an introduction on the topic.
Welcome.
Let me briefly explain
the background of Russia's October Revolution.
[Deng Zhongxia, styled Zhongxie, Student at Peking University]
Russia's October Revolution
took place on 7 November 1917.
[Chen Qiaonian, second eldest son of Chen Duxiu]
That night
under the command
of Bolshevik leader Lenin,
20,000 workers and soldiers
surrounded Petrograd,
and before sunrise gained control of the Winter Palace,
overthrowing the interim government,
establishing the first
dictatorship of the proletariat.
The October Revolution itself
was born under the guidance
of Marxism.
On the day of the successful armed uprising,
the Soviet Union Committee issued
the "Peace Act" and the "Land Act",
in which the "Land Act"
disregards all title deeds
and returns the ownership of land to the state,
for working peasants to use.
This is Marxism's
central socialist principle.
This the background of
Russia's October Revolution.
Thank you.
In my opinion,
the concept of state-owned land is nothing new.
After all, all land belongs to the king in a kingdom.
[Chen Yannian, eldest son of Chen Duxiu]
The essence of the matter has not changed.
Yannian, you are biased.
Let me tell you.
I believe
the October Revolution is a noble action
because it helped turned Marxism's
socialist theory
into reality,
and established
the first socialist country
based on public ownership
and dictatorship of the proletariat
in human history.
This is a historical moment.
It is not wrong to praise it highly.
I disagree.
The October Revolution
fundamentally was still a violent revolution.
In terms of their methods,
it is as violent as the other revolutions that have occurred in the past.
There was no use of new ideas.
The enforcement of common ownership is a novel idea.
But common ownership should be voluntary
with cooperation as the foundation,
instead of the use of force.
Your ideas are typical of anarchism.
It will not apply to China in reality.
Have you tried?
You have never tried,
so you cannot dismiss it as irrelevant to China.
The French philosopher Saint-Simon had tried
and failed.
Saint-Simon tried it out on an island,
it is not practical.
Saint-Simon believed in utopian socialism.
Quiet please!
Students! Students!
Please quiet down.
Quiet down.
Quiet.
I really think that everyone has raised good points.
It seems that there are two sides.
One side is socialism.
The other is anarchism.
Right?
Whoever agrees with socialism, please raise your hand.
Alright put your hands down.
How about anarchism?
A tie.
Chen Duxiu is a hypocrite!
Chen Duxiu, you are not fit to be a teacher!
Chen Duxiu, you have no morals!
Chen Duxiu out of Peking University!
What's going on?
I'm not sure.
He is a teacher.
A hypocrite!
Is this true?
Hypocrites to leave Peking University!
Leave Peking University!
Chen Duxiu has no morals!
Chen Duxiu is a hypocrite!
What's going on?
Hypocrite!
No morals!
Chen Duxiu is a hypocrite!
Scolding me at the doorway doesn't relieve much anger.
Come.
Come inside the garden and scold me.
Stand here and scold me.
Come on.
What's going on?
Chen Duxiu is a hypocrite!
Why don't the two of you come in for a chat?
It's fine, we have food at home.
The food's waiting at home.
Junman, since the thugs have come,
we shan't avoid.
Let us announce it today.
Zhongfu, you don't need to say it.
Ever since I followed you from Anqing,
I have expected the consequences.
I am most familiar with
what kind of person you are.
Even though I am a housewife,
my heart is always with you in every moment.
Don't you always say,
only the immoral will start rumors?
If I minded these small protests,
like the buzzing of mosquitoes and flies,
and became upset,
I would not be
the Gao Junman that you searched for at the start.
Please sign here.
These is your books.
Thank you.
Runzhi.
Mr. Shouchang.
Here.
Sir,
what is this?
This is Peking University's journalism committee.
They are intending to recruit new members.
I have helped you to register.
Mr. Cai has agreed.
This afternoon,
the Commitee will invite
Chief Editor Zhao Piaoping of the "Peking Gazette"
to come
and give a lecture on "Journalism Theory and Practice".
Please have a listen.
This is the admission document.
Have a listen.
Thank you.
This is great.
Mr. Zhao Piaoping.
His reputation preceeds him.
His name is like hearing a thunderclap.
People say he has iron shoulders and hot hands.
Today,
I can finally get to meet him.
Sir,
thank you for your help.
Runzhi,
Zhao Piaoping is not simple.
He is a scholar of the late Qing dynasty.
In 1912,
he assumed the role of Chief Editor of Hangzhou's "Hanmin Daily".
After that,
he was recruited by Director Shi Liangcai of Shanghai's "Shanghai News" (Shen Bao)
to take on the role of special resident journalist in Beijing.
His words are sharp as knives.
He is an all-rounder in the journalistic world.
He started recently at the "Peking Gazette",
assuming the role of director.
His passion is spreading novel ideas.
Attending his lessons
will allow you to learn a lot.
That's great.
Sir,
if I attend lessons in the afternoon,
what will happen to the work here?
I'm still here.
Please don't worry.
Mr. Shouchang.
Sir,
I'm here to return a book.
Follow me.
Go.
Sir.
Thank you.
Come, student.
Three books.
Alright.
Welcome students.
Principal Cai has started this conference
called the Journalist conference.
Students, what does journalism mean to you?
[Zhao Piaoping, Chief Editor of the "Peking Gazette"]
What is the specific content
of this conference?
I think
this is the basic knowledge
that everyone here needs to know.
I believe
we need to look at the following points:
the foundations of news;
choosing the right topics for a newspaper;
how to collate news articles;
how to edit news articles;
how to transmit news;
et cetera.
In conclusion,
this is a complete study of what constitutes the news.
I know
everyone here
desires to become a journalist.
So I will like to invite
someone in this current society
to share what are the basic principles that one needs to have
in order to become a qualified journalist.
Please speak freely.
I am all ears.